<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NASA Space Station Blog</title>
    <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/</link>
    <description>The official blog of NASA's space station news.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Spacewalk Preps Focus on Robotics; Earth and Piloting Studies Round Out Day</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/22/spacewalk-preps-focus-on-robotics-earth-and-piloting-studies-round-out-day/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25938" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25938" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qGrphn"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25938" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams is pictured during a six-hour spacewalk on Jan. 16, 2025, for science and maintenance on the International Space Station." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25938" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams is pictured during a six-hour spacewalk on Jan. 16, 2025, for science and maintenance on the International Space Station.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacewalk preparations continue aboard the International Space Station to remove communications gear and search for microbes next week. The Expedition 72 crew members also worked on a host of advanced science experiments and housecleaning duties throughout the day on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; are slated to begin their spacewalk at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-to-cover-two-spacewalks-hold-preview-news-conference/"&gt;8 a.m. EST on Jan. 30&lt;/a&gt; and spend about six-and-a-half hours removing a radio frequency group antenna assembly and searching for microbes on the orbital outpost. The duo kicked off their day inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; reviewing their spacewalk procedures and servicing their spacesuit helmets. Afterward, Williams and Wilmore checked the fuel and power capacity of their SAFER or Simplified Aid for EVA Rescue. A spacewalker would use the SAFER installed on their spacesuit to maneuver back to the station in the unlikely event they became untethered from the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; will assist the spacewalkers next week and studied on Wednesday the spacewalking tasks and the Canadarm2 robotic maneuvers they will use to support the removal of the radio communications gear. Hague, with Pettit as backup, will be at the controls of the Canadarm2 carefully guiding Williams, who will be attached to the robotic arm’s tip, or latching end effector. Pettit and Hague will also help the spacewalkers in and out of their spacesuits, guide the duo in and out of Quest, and monitor the spacewalking activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of their shifts, the four NASA astronauts regrouped inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt; to clean up and reorganize cargo. The quartet disposed of trash, relocated hardware to gain more space, and conducted a photographic inspection of Harmony for analysis on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Earth observations and advanced space piloting studies were on the schedule aboard the orbiting lab’s Roscosmos segment. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov first set up a camera with a spectrometer and pointed it out a window on the Zvezda service module to photograph the effects of Earth disasters in numerous wavelengths. Next, he strapped on a sensor-packed cap that recorded his reactions as he practiced on a computer spacecraft and robotic piloting techniques crew members may use on future planetary missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Cosmonaut Alexey Ovchinin began his shift servicing audio and ventilation systems in the Zvezda and Zarya modules then wrapped his day exploring 3D printing tools in microgravity. Flight Engineer Ivan Vagner spent his day activating video gear and uninstalling electronics hardware before taking a questionnaire documenting his experience communicating with international crews and mission controllers from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376.jpg" alt="Spacewalk Preps Focus on Robotics; Earth and Piloting Studies Round Out Day"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/22/spacewalk-preps-focus-on-robotics-earth-and-piloting-studies-round-out-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combustion, Biology Studies and Housecleaning Duties Fill Station Crew’s Day</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/23/combustion-biology-studies-and-housecleaning-duties-fill-station-crews-day/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25943" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25943" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qGxaGA"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25943" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488176.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams (center) is dwarfed near the SpaceX Dragon crew spacecraft as she replaces advanced navigational hardware during a spacewalk on Jan. 16, 2025." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488176.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488176.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488176.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25943" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams (center) is dwarfed near the SpaceX Dragon crew spacecraft as she replaces advanced navigational hardware during a spacewalk on Jan. 16, 2025.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew took a break from spacewalk preparations on Thursday and focused on combustion and biology research. The seven orbital residents also worked on housecleaning duties and lab maintenance ensuring the upkeep of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; turned her attention to cleaning crew quarters and filming an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9179"&gt;educational video&lt;/a&gt; following several days of preparing for her spacewalk with NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;. Williams first cleaned ducts, fans, and air sensors inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s port side crew quarters. Next, she filmed a video demonstrating how water moves and evaporates in microgravity for students and teachers on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilmore worked in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/unity-module/"&gt;Unity module&lt;/a&gt; and inventoried tools that fellow NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; will use to support the spacewalkers next week. Williams and Wilmore are planning to begin a spacewalk at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-to-cover-two-spacewalks-hold-preview-news-conference/"&gt;8 a.m. EST on Jan. 30&lt;/a&gt; to remove radio antenna hardware and search for microbes outside the orbital outpost. Hague and Pettit will help the spacewalking duo in and out of the spacesuits, in and out of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt;, and maneuver the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; during the planned six-and-a-half-hour excursion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hague had the first half of his day off before he spent the second part of his shift cleaning ducts, fans, and air sensors inside Harmony’s overhead crew quarters. Pettit worked throughout the day configuring research hardware inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=317"&gt;Combustion Integrated Rack&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8268"&gt;spacecraft fire safety investigation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner began their day working on separate human research experiments. Ovchinin attached sensors to himself measuring how microgravity affects a crew member’s vascular function. Vagner participated in a breathing study that monitors crews for potential space-caused respiratory system issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov inventoried hardware stowed throughout the space station’s Roscosmos segment then serviced an oxygen generator in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;. Next, he installed and configured observation hardware to image Earth’s nighttime atmosphere in near-ultraviolet wavelengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488176.jpg" alt="Combustion, Biology Studies and Housecleaning Duties Fill Station Crew’s Day"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/23/combustion-biology-studies-and-housecleaning-duties-fill-station-crews-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spacesuit Work and Life Science Wrap Up Week Aboard Station</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/24/spacesuit-work-and-life-science-wrap-up-week-aboard-station/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25948" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25948" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qH2Rct"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25948" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e518423.jpg" alt="Astronaut Don Pettit's reflection is pictured on the helmet visor of a spacesuit in this photograph he took inside the Quest airlock." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e518423.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e518423.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e518423.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25948" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Don Pettit’s reflection is pictured on the helmet visor of a spacesuit in this photograph he took inside the Quest airlock.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week ended aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; with spacesuit maintenance and research into how microgravity affects blood pressure and breathing. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; residents also serviced a variety of hardware supporting science experiments and life support systems aboard the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two NASA astronauts, Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;, continued gearing up for a spacewalk scheduled to begin at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-to-cover-two-spacewalks-hold-preview-news-conference/"&gt;8 a.m. EST on Thursday, Jan. 30&lt;/a&gt;. Williams worked throughout Friday in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; completing the charging of lithium-ion batteries that power spacesuits for the duration of a spacewalk. Next, she filtered and cleaned the water loops that cool astronauts in their spacesuits in the extreme environment of outer space. Wilmore pitched in and verified the functionality of spacesuit components including glove heaters, cameras, and helmet lights. The duo is preparing for a six-and-a-half-hour spacewalk next week to remove radio antenna hardware and search for microbes outside the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; began his day inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; installing experiment containers on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=66"&gt;BioLab&lt;/a&gt;, a biology research device that enables observations of microbes, cells, tissues, and more in weightlessness. NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; activated life support gear in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/unity-module/"&gt;Unity module&lt;/a&gt; and removed more life support hardware from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;. The pair later met at the end of the day and reviewed procedures they will use in the future to service the external thermal control system that cools hardware on the outside of the orbital lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner started their day on human research. This time, Ovchinin wore sensors that measured his exhalation following a deep breath helping doctors understand how microgravity affects the respiratory system. Vagner wore a separate set of sensors for a study observing how a crew member’s vascular system functions during a long-term space mission. Cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov spent the first part of his day on orbital plumbing tasks in the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/07/29/new-module-successfully-docks-to-space-station/"&gt;Nauka science module&lt;/a&gt; then wrapped up his shift auditing stowage space throughout the station’s Roscosmos segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e518423.jpg" alt="Spacesuit Work and Life Science Wrap Up Week Aboard Station"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/24/spacesuit-work-and-life-science-wrap-up-week-aboard-station/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spacewalk Robotics Training, Red Lettuce Harvesting Kick Off Week</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/27/spacewalk-robotics-training-red-lettuce-harvesting-kick-off-week/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25955" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25955" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qGrphn"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25955" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376_7a852f.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams is pictured during a six-hour spacewalk for science and maintenance on the International Space Station on Jan. 16, 2025." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376_7a852f.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376_7a852f.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376_7a852f.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25955" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams is pictured during a six-hour spacewalk for science and maintenance on the International Space Station on Jan. 16, 2025.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparations continue for a spacewalk to remove communications hardware and check for microbes outside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; later this week. Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew harvested red lettuce for a space agriculture study and continued its upkeep of the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; are scheduled to begin a six-and-a-half-hour spacewalk at 8 a.m. EST on Thursday. The NASA astronauts will remove a degraded radio frequency group antenna assembly and collect samples of potential microbes living outside of the orbital outpost. The duo reviewed on Monday the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; procedures necessary to support the removal of the degraded radio communications gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; will be at the controls of the Canadarm2 on Thursday assisting and monitoring the spacewalkers. The two NASA astronauts also studied the robotics procedures and practiced on a computer the maneuvers they will use to guide the spacewalkers during their external maintenance activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was still time during the day for Wilmore and Hague to join each other in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; and pick a small crop of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;red lettuce&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt;. Wilmore started the harvesting job collecting the leaves, packing them in pouches, and stowing the samples in a science freezer for later analysis. Pettit finished the botany operations extracting roots from the Plant Habitat, collecting water samples for analysis, and photographing the research hardware. The botany investigation is assessing the nutritional value of food grown in space and may promote growing crops on future missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and Pettit partnered together inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/permanent-multipurpose-module/"&gt;Permanent Multipurpose Module (PMM)&lt;/a&gt; cleaning and organizing a variety of cargo including food, electronics gear, science experiments and more. The PMM was launched to the station on space shuttle Discovery and installed on &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/unity-module/"&gt;Unity module&lt;/a&gt;’s Earth-facing port March 1, 2011. PMM was relocated May 27, 2015, to its current location on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth observations, space navigation, and lab maintenance topped the schedule for the three cosmonauts working in the orbiting lab’s Roscosmos segment. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov outfitted a camera with specialized hardware and photographed Earth landmarks to study the effects &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22uragan%22&amp;amp;i=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;natural and man-made catastrophes&lt;/a&gt;. Flight Engineer Alexey Ovchinin explored ways to acquire more accurate &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=116"&gt;space station navigation data&lt;/a&gt; from ground and satellite navigation systems. Flight Engineer Ivan Vagner deactivated and dismantled obsolete communications hardware that has been replaced with an updated command and telemetry system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e488376_7a852f.jpg" alt="Spacewalk Robotics Training, Red Lettuce Harvesting Kick Off Week"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/27/spacewalk-robotics-training-red-lettuce-harvesting-kick-off-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Preps for Thursday Spacewalk and Works Space Gardening</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/28/crew-preps-for-thursday-spacewalk-and-works-space-gardening/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25968" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25968" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qH1TP3"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25968" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e517812.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams is pictured during maintenance activities inside the International Space Station's Unity module." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e517812.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e517812.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e517812.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25968" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams is pictured during maintenance activities inside the International Space Station’s Unity module.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacewalk preparations and space gardening were the main duties aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday. The seven &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crewmates also serviced electronics systems and packed a cargo craft for its upcoming departure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; began their day with standard health checks required for astronauts getting ready for a spacewalk. The duo checked vital signs including temperature, blood pressure, and breathing rate then transferred the data to a tablet computer for review by doctors on the ground. Both astronauts later gathered inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; and continued to gather and organize their spacewalking hardware including tethers, pistol grip tools, and other task-specific gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and Wilmore are due to set their spacesuits to battery power at 8 a.m. EST on Thursday signifying the official start time of the second spacewalk of 2025. The two NASA astronauts will exit Quest and spend about six-and-a-half hours removing radio communications hardware and searching for microbes outside the orbital outpost. &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/u-s-spacewalk-92/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt; will begin its live spacewalk coverage at 6:30 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; participated in the spacewalk preparations Tuesday collecting the hardware necessary to remove the radio frequency group antenna assembly. Next, he photographed the tools Williams and Wilmore staged inside Quest for documentation. Hague wrapped up his shift reconfiguring computer network hardware then resupplying medical kits with blood tubes, needles, gloves, and more inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22human+research+facility%22&amp;amp;i=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;Human Research Facility&lt;/a&gt; racks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; spent his day working on space agricultural hardware to learn how to grow food in space and sustain future crews on long-term missions to the Moon, Mars, and beyond. The four-time station visitor first watered &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9013"&gt;thale cress plants&lt;/a&gt; growing to understand the effects of microgravity and ultraviolet radiation on plant life. Afterward, Pettit removed research components from inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; that recently hosted a small crop of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;red lettuce&lt;/a&gt; that was harvested and preserved and will soon be tested for its nutritional value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise research, cargo packing, and lab maintenance topped the schedule for the cosmonauts working in the Roscosmos segment of the orbiting lab. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov attached electrodes to himself and jogged on a treadmill for a physical fitness evaluation in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;. Flight Engineer Alexey Ovchinin spent his day loading trash and discarded gear inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;Progress 89&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft due to depart Zvezda next month. Flight Engineer Ivan Vagner spent his day inside Zvezda installing new command and telemetry hardware that can communicate with Soyuz and Progress spacecraft, ground stations, and orbiting satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e517812.jpg" alt="Crew Preps for Thursday Spacewalk and Works Space Gardening"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/28/crew-preps-for-thursday-spacewalk-and-works-space-gardening/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Ready for Thursday Spacewalk, Keeps Up Space Agriculture Research</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/29/crew-ready-for-thursday-spacewalk-keeps-up-space-agriculture-research/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25975" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25975" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qHTs1P"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25975" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e572188.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams works in the Quest airlock readying a pair of spacesuits that she and astronaut Nick Hague will wear during a spacewalk on Jan. 30, 2025." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e572188.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e572188.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e572188.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25975" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams works in the Quest airlock readying a pair of spacesuits that she and astronaut Nick Hague will wear during a spacewalk on Jan. 30, 2025.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew members have completed preparations for a science and maintenance spacewalk scheduled for Thursday. Space agriculture, Earth observations, and lab maintenance rounded out the day for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;, two NASA astronauts who are scheduled to begin a spacewalk at 8 a.m. EST on Thursday, have completed their procedure reviews and spacesuit checks. They also joined NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; and practiced on a computer the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; maneuvers necessary to remove radio communications hardware, the first of two main spacewalking tasks. The second main task will see the two spacewalkers swab sites outside the orbital outpost to collect samples of potential microbes for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hague began his day in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; making space and readying the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1891"&gt;Astrobee&lt;/a&gt; robotic free flyers for operations testing their ability to downlink video and imagery to mission controllers in real time. Pettit was back on space gardening duty processing samples and installing research hardware for an investigation exploring &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9013"&gt;how microgravity and ultraviolet radiation affect plant growth&lt;/a&gt;. Results may enable future crews to grow crops on spacecraft for sustainment during long-term space missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three cosmonauts working in the Roscosmos segment of the orbiting lab focused on imaging Earth landmarks and installing new electronics hardware. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov once again set up a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22uragan%22&amp;amp;i=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;camera with a spectrometer&lt;/a&gt; attach&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ed and photographed areas along the Mediterranean Sea in a variety of wavelengths, including Libya and Greece. Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner continued installing new command and telemetry gear in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt; that can communicate with Soyuz and Progress spacecraft, ground stations, and orbiting satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e572188.jpg" alt="Crew Ready for Thursday Spacewalk, Keeps Up Space Agriculture Research"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/29/crew-ready-for-thursday-spacewalk-keeps-up-space-agriculture-research/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA+ is Live Covering Spacewalk for Radio Hardware Removal, Microbe Search</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/nasa-is-live-covering-spacewalk-for-radio-hardware-removal-microbe-search/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25977" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25977" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825b.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25977" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825b.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Butch Wilmore will exit the International Space Station's Quest airlock to conduct a science and maintenance spacewalk." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825b.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825b.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825b.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25977" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Butch Wilmore will exit the International Space Station’s Quest airlock to conduct a science and maintenance spacewalk.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA’s coverage is underway on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/u-s-spacewalk-92/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt; as two astronauts will conduct a spacewalk outside the International Space Station. The spacewalk is scheduled to begin at approximately 8 a.m. EST and last about six and a half hours.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/watch-nasa-programming/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Butch Wilmore will exit the station’s Quest airlock to remove a radio frequency group antenna assembly from the station’s truss, collect samples of surface material for analysis from the Destiny laboratory and the Quest airlock to see whether microorganisms may exist on the exterior of the orbital complex, and prepare a spare elbow joint for the Canadarm2 robotic arm in the event it is needed for a replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams will serve as spacewalk crew member 1 and wear a suit with red stripes. Wilmore will serve as spacewalk crew member 2 and wear an unmarked suit. This spacewalk will be Williams’ ninth and Wilmore’s fifth, and it will be the 274th &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/station/spacewalks/"&gt;spacewalk&lt;/a&gt; in support of space station assembly, maintenance, and upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825b.jpg" alt="NASA+ is Live Covering Spacewalk for Radio Hardware Removal, Microbe Search"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/nasa-is-live-covering-spacewalk-for-radio-hardware-removal-microbe-search/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA Astronauts Begin Spacewalk for Maintenance and Science</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/nasa-astronauts-begin-spacewalk-for-maintenance-and-science/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25979" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25979" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25979" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams (left) is conducting her ninth career spacewalk and Butch Wilmore (right) is conducting his fifth career spacewalk today." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25979" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams (left) is conducting her ninth career spacewalk and Butch Wilmore (right) is conducting his fifth career spacewalk today.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Butch Wilmore began a spacewalk at approximately 7:43 a.m. EST to remove a radio frequency group antenna assembly from the station’s truss, collect samples of surface material for analysis from the Destiny laboratory and the Quest airlock to see whether microorganisms may exist on the exterior of the orbital complex, and prepare a spare elbow joint for the Canadarm2 robotic arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA’s coverage continues on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/u-s-spacewalk-92/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/watch-nasa-programming/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams is crew member 1, wearing a suit with red stripes. Wilmore is spacewalk crew member 2, wearing an unmarked suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_butch_012825.jpg" alt="NASA Astronauts Begin Spacewalk for Maintenance and Science"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/nasa-astronauts-begin-spacewalk-for-maintenance-and-science/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spacewalkers Complete Radio Hardware Removal and Microbe Search</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/spacewalkers-complete-radio-hardware-removal-and-microbe-search/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25987" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25987" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_canadarm2_013025.jpg"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25987" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_canadarm2_013025.jpg" alt="NASA spacewalker Suni Williams is attached to the tip of the Canadarm2 robotic arm as the International Space Station orbited 260 miles above the Earth. Credit: NASA+" width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_canadarm2_013025.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_canadarm2_013025.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_canadarm2_013025.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25987" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA spacewalker Suni Williams is attached to the tip of the Canadarm2 robotic arm as the International Space Station orbited 260 miles above the Earth. Credit: NASA+&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts Suni Williams and&amp;nbsp;Butch Wilmore concluded their spacewalk at&amp;nbsp;1:09 p.m. EST Jan. 30. It was the&amp;nbsp;ninth spacewalk for&amp;nbsp;Williams and the&amp;nbsp;fifth for&amp;nbsp;Wilmore, and it was the 274th&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/station/spacewalks/"&gt;spacewalk&lt;/a&gt; in support of space station assembly, maintenance, and upgrades. Williams surpassed former NASA astronaut Peggy Whitson’s record for total spacewalking time by a female astronaut. Williams now has 62 hours, 6 minutes of total spacewalk time, fourth on NASA’s all-time list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and&amp;nbsp;Wilmore completed their primary&amp;nbsp;objectives, including removing a radio frequency group antenna assembly from the station’s truss and collecting samples of surface material for analysis from the Destiny laboratory and the Quest airlock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_suni_canadarm2_013025.jpg" alt="Spacewalkers Complete Radio Hardware Removal and Microbe Search"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/spacewalkers-complete-radio-hardware-removal-and-microbe-search/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronauts Relax After Spacewalk, Cosmonauts Work Physics and Exercise Research</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/31/astronauts-relax-after-spacewalk-cosmonauts-work-physics-and-exercise-research/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25992" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25992" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qJcJXV"&gt;&lt;img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25992" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e574907.jpg" alt="NASA spacewalker Suni Williams is attached to the Canadarm2 robotic arm's latching end effector while being maneuvered 264 miles above the South Pacific Ocean." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e574907.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e574907.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e574907.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25992" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA spacewalker Suni Williams is attached to the Canadarm2 robotic arm’s latching end effector while being maneuvered 264 miles above the South Pacific Ocean.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two spacewalkers and their assisting crew members took a half-day off on Friday following the previous day’s excursion to remove radio hardware and swab for microbes outside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt;. The rest of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew researched plasma physics, took a physical fitness test, and ensured the upkeep of the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; took Friday morning off sleeping in after conducting a &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/30/spacewalkers-complete-radio-hardware-removal-and-microbe-search/"&gt;five-hour and 26-minute spacewalk&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday. The duo worked in the vacuum of space removing a radio frequency group assembly and collecting samples of potential microbes living on the outside of the station for analysis. During that same spacewalk Williams surpassed Peggy Whitson’s record for most total spacewalking time by a female of 60 hours and 21 minutes. Williams now has 62 hours, 6 minutes of total spacewalk time, fourth on NASA’s all-time list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and Wilmore then spent Friday afternoon servicing their spacesuits and cleaning the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; where they staged Thursday’s spacewalk. At the end of the workday, the pair was joined by NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; for a standard conference with mission controllers discussing issues or concerns they may have experienced during the spacewalk. Hague and Pettit, the day before, had assisted the spacewalkers in and out of their spacesuits and operated the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams total spacewalking time is now 62 hours and six minutes over nine spacewalks. Wilmore has completed five spacewalks reaching 31 hours and two minutes of total spacewalking time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expedition 72’s other three crewmates, Roscosmos Flight Engineers Aleksandr Gorbunov, Alexey Ovchinin, and Ivan Vagner, had a busy day studying space physics, pedaling on an exercise cycle, and installing new electronics gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gorbunov reviewed operations for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=1192"&gt;Plasma Kristall-4&lt;/a&gt; experiment that observes the behavior of complex plasmas in microgravity. The plasmas contain electrons, ions, neutral gas, and microparticles that interact strongly when charged and can turn into plasma crystals. Next, he installed a video monitor in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; to support the plasma crystal study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ovchinin and Vagner started their day pedaling on an exercise cycle for an hour each while attached to sensors measuring their health data. The regularly scheduled fitness tests help researchers understand how microgravity affects a crew member’s body. The duo then spent the second half of their day continuing to install new command and telemetry gear inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2025/01/blog_iss072e574907.jpg" alt="Astronauts Relax After Spacewalk, Cosmonauts Work Physics and Exercise Research"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2025/01/31/astronauts-relax-after-spacewalk-cosmonauts-work-physics-and-exercise-research/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
