<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NASA Space Station Blog</title>
    <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/</link>
    <description>The official blog of NASA's space station news.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 05:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>NASA SpaceX Crew-8 Flight Readiness Review Concludes, Teleconference to Follow</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/25/nasa-spacex-crew-8-flight-readiness-review-concludes-teleconference-to-follow/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/25/nasa-spacex-crew-8-flight-readiness-review-concludes-teleconference-to-follow/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Flight Readiness Review (FRR) for NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 mission to the International Space Station has concluded, and teams are proceeding toward a planned liftoff at 12:04 a.m. EST on Friday, March 1, from Launch Complex 39A at the agency’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA will hold a media teleconference at 7:30 p.m. EST to discuss the outcome of the review. Listen live on NASA’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants in the teleconference are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Bowersox, associate administrator, Space Operations Mission Directorate, NASA Headquarters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Stich, manager, NASA’s Commercial Crew Program, Kennedy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joel Montalbano, manager, International Space Station Program, NASA’s Johnson Space Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emily Nelson, chief flight director, NASA’s Johnson Space Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William Gerstenmaier, vice president, Build and Flight Reliability, SpaceX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eric van der Wal, Houston office team leader, ESA (European Space Agency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Takayoshi Nishikawa, director, JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) Houston Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later tonight, SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon spacecraft, named Endeavour, will roll&amp;nbsp;out&amp;nbsp;to the pad at Launch Complex 39A. On Tuesday, Feb. 27, the crew will participate in a rehearsal of launch day activities ahead of an integrated static fire test in preparation for liftoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt;, commander;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/michael-reed-barratt/"&gt;Michael Barratt&lt;/a&gt;, pilot; &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt;, mission specialist; along with Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin, mission specialist, will fly to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; aboard the Dragon spacecraft. As part of the agency’s Commercial Crew Program, Crew-8 marks the ninth human spaceflight mission on SpaceX’s Dragon spacecraft and the eighth crew rotation mission to the space station since 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details about the mission and NASA’s Commercial Crew Program can be found by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;Crew-8 blog&lt;/a&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/"&gt;commercial crew blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/commercial_crew"&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NASACommercialCrew"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/25/nasa-spacex-crew-8-flight-readiness-review-concludes-teleconference-to-follow/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/25/nasa-spacex-crew-8-flight-readiness-review-concludes-teleconference-to-follow/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Station Crew Explores Space Health as Dragon Crew Nears Launch</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/26/station-crew-explores-space-health-as-dragon-crew-nears-launch/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/26/station-crew-explores-space-health-as-dragon-crew-nears-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_23547" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-23547" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2pAeuF2"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-23547" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_crew8_ksc_022524.jpg" alt="The four SpaceX Crew-8 members are pictured shortly after arriving at Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Feb. 25, 2024. Credit: NASA/Kim Shiflett" width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_crew8_ksc_022524.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_crew8_ksc_022524-300x169.jpg 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_crew8_ksc_022524-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-23547" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The four SpaceX Crew-8 members are pictured shortly after arriving at Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Feb. 25, 2024. Credit: NASA/Kim Shiflett&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human research, space physics, and airlock operations started the week for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-70/"&gt;Expedition 70&lt;/a&gt; crew aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/cupola/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt;. Back on Earth, four Commercial Crew members are counting down to their launch aboard the SpaceX Dragon spacecraft to the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercising daily in space is critical to maintain crew health due to the effects of living long-term in weightlessness. Astronauts work out on specialized exercise gear designed specifically for the microgravity environment including a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;treadmill&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=821"&gt;exercise cycle&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=973"&gt;advanced resistive exercise device&lt;/a&gt;. Doctors frequently monitor these exercise sessions while crew members are attached to sensors, electrodes, and breathing gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/moghbeli-j.pdf#_blank"&gt;Jasmin Moghbeli&lt;/a&gt; of NASA and &lt;a href="https://humans-in-space.jaxa.jp/en/astronaut/furukawa-satoshi/"&gt;Satoshi Furukawa&lt;/a&gt; of JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) took turns pedaling on the exercise cycle Monday morning for a workout study. The duo exercised inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/destiny-laboratory-module/"&gt;Destiny laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; for the regularly scheduled aerobics and fitness test that measures heart and breathing rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moghbeli then moved on and joined NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ohara-l.pdf#_blank"&gt;Loral O’Hara&lt;/a&gt; to work on the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2020/12/21/new-science-airlock-expands-stations-research-capacity/"&gt;NanoRacks Bishop airlock&lt;/a&gt; inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;. Both astronauts spent Monday afternoon reconfiguring Bishop after it was reattached to Tranquility following a week of experimental &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8838"&gt;GITAI-S2&lt;/a&gt; robotics tests. The autonomous robotic arm demonstration explores using automated robots to build habitats and spacecraft on future lunar and planetary missions. Furukawa also assisted with the airlock work after he inspected hatches in the U.S. segment of the space station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physics was also on the research schedule as O’Hara and Commander &lt;a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Human_and_Robotic_Exploration/Astronauts/Andreas_Mogensen"&gt;Andreas Mogensen&lt;/a&gt; from ESA (European Space Agency) serviced samples and hardware for a pair of different experiments. O’Hara swapped optic fiber samples inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=341"&gt;Microgravity Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt; for an investigation exploring how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8850"&gt;manufacture fiber optic cables&lt;/a&gt; superior to those produced on Earth. Mogensen replaced components inside the Combustion Integrated Rack for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8266"&gt;space fire safety experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub had a fitness evaluation on Monday as he jogged on a treadmill with electrodes attached to his chest measuring his heart rate. Cosmonauts Oleg Kononenko and Konstantin Borisov tried on a suit being tested for its ability to help crew members adjust to Earth’s gravity after living for months or years in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the space station is orbiting higher after the docked &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/17/resupply-ship-docks-to-station-completing-space-delivery/"&gt;Progress 87&lt;/a&gt; resupply ship fired its engines for over 17 minutes on Friday. The orbital reboost positions the station for next month’s launch of the Soyuz MS-25 crew ship and the departure of the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2023/09/15/soyuz-docks-to-space-station-with-new-crew/"&gt;Soyuz MS-24&lt;/a&gt; crew ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on Earth, four Commercial Crew members representing the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; mission are at the Kennedy Space Center in Florida preparing for their launch aboard the SpaceX Dragon Endeavour spacecraft. Commander Matt Dominick, Pilot Mike Barratt, and Mission Specialists Jeanette Epps and Alexander Grebenkin will lift off aboard Dragon at 12:04 a.m. EST on Friday. They will dock to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port at 6 a.m. on Saturday beginning a six-month space research mission on the orbital lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/26/station-crew-explores-space-health-as-dragon-crew-nears-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_crew8_ksc_022524.jpg" alt="Station Crew Explores Space Health as Dragon Crew Nears Launch"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/26/station-crew-explores-space-health-as-dragon-crew-nears-launch/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expedition 70 Crew Works on Station Airlocks and Exercise Research</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/27/expedition-70-crew-works-on-station-airlocks-and-exercise-research/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/27/expedition-70-crew-works-on-station-airlocks-and-exercise-research/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_23569" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-23569" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2penJkX"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-23569" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e014305.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts (from left) Loral O'Hara and Jasmin Moghbeli work on spacesuit maintenance inside the Quest airlock." width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e014305.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e014305-300x169.jpg 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e014305-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-23569" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts (from left) Loral O’Hara and Jasmin Moghbeli work on spacesuit maintenance inside the Quest airlock.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-70/"&gt;Expedition 70&lt;/a&gt; crew focused mainly on operational maintenance activities throughout Tuesday. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/cupola/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also continued their exercise research among a host of other ongoing science experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airlock activities filled the day for NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ohara-l.pdf#_blank"&gt;Loral O’Hara&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/moghbeli-j.pdf#_blank"&gt;Jasmin Moghbeli&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S. segment of the orbital lab. The duo started the day in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt; and finalized reconfiguring the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2020/12/21/new-science-airlock-expands-stations-research-capacity/"&gt;NanoRacks Bishop airlock&lt;/a&gt; following a week of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8838"&gt;experimental robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; activities. Afterward, the NASA pair moved into the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; and serviced a pair of spacesuits then prepared Quest for upcoming advanced air conditioning work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Human_and_Robotic_Exploration/Astronauts/Andreas_Mogensen"&gt;Andreas Mogensen&lt;/a&gt; from ESA (European Space Agency) worked inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; during the morning swapping out life support gear. Later, he set up the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8444"&gt;Lumina&lt;/a&gt; radiation detection experiment hardware in Columbus that measures in real time the fluctuating radiation environment aboard the space station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) astronaut &lt;a href="https://humans-in-space.jaxa.jp/en/astronaut/furukawa-satoshi/"&gt;Satoshi Furukawa&lt;/a&gt; had a busy schedule as he worked on biology and robotics research all day. Furukawa first swapped sensors and checked vents on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=333"&gt;Cell Biology Experiment Facility&lt;/a&gt; located in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;. Next, Furukawa checked out the performance of a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8065"&gt;free-flying camera robot&lt;/a&gt; inside Kibo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Furukawa spent the rest of Tuesday participating in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8413"&gt;CIPHER&lt;/a&gt; experiment, a suite of 14 human research studies to understand the effects of weightlessness on the body. He began with deadlift exercises on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=973"&gt;advanced resistive exercise device&lt;/a&gt; for one portion of the study. Next, he wore the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7392"&gt;Bio-Monitor&lt;/a&gt; vest and headband recording his physiological data then calibrated breathing gear. CIPHER is providing doctors vital insights that may help keep crews safe and healthy on longer term missions to the Moon, Mars, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three astronauts and Roscosmos Flight Engineer Konstantin Borisov also spent an hour each throughout the day packing for their upcoming departure and return to Earth. The quartet will undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s space-facing port aboard the SpaceX Dragon Endurance spacecraft a week after the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; members arrive. Crew-8 is due to launch at 12:04 a.m. EST on Friday aboard the SpaceX Dragon Endeavour spacecraft and dock to Harmony’s forward port on Saturday at 7 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veteran cosmonaut Oleg Kononenko and Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub spent most of the day installing cargo containers inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt;. Kononenko later jogged on a treadmill while attached to electrodes and sensors for a regularly scheduled fitness assessment at the end of the day. Daily exercise aboard the station is necessary for crews to maintain bone and muscle health due to the lack of gravity. Borisov also worked on computer and ventilation maintenance in the station’s Roscosmos segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/27/expedition-70-crew-works-on-station-airlocks-and-exercise-research/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e014305.jpg" alt="Expedition 70 Crew Works on Station Airlocks and Exercise Research"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/27/expedition-70-crew-works-on-station-airlocks-and-exercise-research/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space-Caused Eye, Head Pressure Research as Crew-8 Preps for Launch</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/28/space-caused-eye-head-pressure-research-as-crew-8-preps-for-launch/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/28/space-caused-eye-head-pressure-research-as-crew-8-preps-for-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_23577" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-23577" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2pyosWj"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-23577" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e090470.jpg" alt="The seven-member Expedition 70 crew gathers for a dinner time portrait inside the International Space Station's Unity module." width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e090470.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e090470-300x169.jpg 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e090470-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-23577" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The seven-member Expedition 70 crew gathers for a dinner time portrait inside the International Space Station’s Unity module.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eye checks and “anti-gravity” suits were the main human research topics for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-70/"&gt;Expedition 70&lt;/a&gt; crew on Wednesday. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/cupola/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also worked on standard maintenance tasks while getting ready for the next Commercial Crew swap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctors are constantly monitoring astronauts’ health to ensure long-term mission success and ease their return to Earth’s gravity after months or years in space. Vision is a critical parameter as researchers explore space-caused pressure on the eyes due to fluids shifting toward the head. The same fluid shifts quickly reverse when an astronaut reenters Earth’s atmosphere causing blood pressure and stability issues. Doctors are studying methods to offset these symptoms and reduce the time it takes for crews to adapt to gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ohara-l.pdf#_blank"&gt;Loral O’Hara&lt;/a&gt; had her optical nerve, retina, and cornea scanned on Wednesday using standard medical imaging hardware. JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://humans-in-space.jaxa.jp/en/astronaut/furukawa-satoshi/"&gt;Satoshi Furukawa&lt;/a&gt; led the eye exams operating the optical gear in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt; with assistance from doctors and technicians on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the day, O’Hara wore a sensor-packed vest and headband, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7392"&gt;Bio-Monitor&lt;/a&gt; gear from the Canadian Space Agency, being evaluated for their ability to comfortably monitor an astronaut’s health data. Furukawa continued setting up &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=333"&gt;biology hardware&lt;/a&gt; for upcoming research inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two cosmonauts, Nikolai Chub and Konstantin Borisov, tried on the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/ISS_Science_Blog/2015/06/02/rubber-vacuum-pants-that-suck/"&gt;lower body negative pressure suit&lt;/a&gt; again in the middle of the week exploring its potential to decrease fluid pressure in the head triggered by weightlessness. Doctors theorize the downward fluid shifts may help maintain a crew member’s heart rate and blood pressure when returning to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/moghbeli-j.pdf#_blank"&gt;Jasmin Moghbeli&lt;/a&gt; from NASA and &lt;a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Human_and_Robotic_Exploration/Astronauts/Andreas_Mogensen"&gt;Andreas Mogensen&lt;/a&gt; from ESA (European Space Agency) joined forces and spent the day inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; replacing advanced air conditioning equipment. The duo swapped hoses, seals, and a heat exchanger on the Common Cabin Air Assembly, a life support device that circulates, cools, and dehumidifies the station’s air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moghbeli and Mogensen, Commander and Pilot of the SpaceX Crew-7 mission, also continued packing gear for their return to Earth inside the SpaceX Dragon “Endurance” spacecraft. The duo along with Furukawa and Borisov are scheduled to depart the station ending their mission about one week after the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; mission arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crew-8, led by Commander Matthew Dominick with Pilot Michael Barratt and Mission Specialists Jeanette Epps and Alexander Grebenkin, have been given the go to launch to the station at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-sets-coverage-for-agencys-spacex-crew-8-launch-docking/"&gt;12:04 a.m. EST on Friday&lt;/a&gt; aboard the SpaceX Dragon “Endeavour” spacecraft. The Commercial Crew quartet will take an automated ride aboard Dragon for a docking to Harmony’s forward port at 7 a.m. on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA and SpaceX are also targeting no earlier than mid-March for launch of the company’s 30th commercial resupply services mission to the International Space Station. Liftoff of the SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon cargo spacecraft is scheduled from Space Launch Complex 40 at Cape Canaveral Space Force Station in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the NASA Administrator’s Briefing from Kennedy Space Center today, NASA’s International Space Station Program Manager Joel Montalbano &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/H67Bq5fttWk?si=gAdXIQyO_AzyWAOG&amp;amp;t=1333"&gt;discussed the upcoming crew and cargo missions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/28/space-caused-eye-head-pressure-research-as-crew-8-preps-for-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_iss070e090470.jpg" alt="Space-Caused Eye, Head Pressure Research as Crew-8 Preps for Launch"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/28/space-caused-eye-head-pressure-research-as-crew-8-preps-for-launch/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Day Aboard Station as Crew-8 Launch Moves</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/29/maintenance-day-aboard-station-as-crew-8-launch-moves/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/29/maintenance-day-aboard-station-as-crew-8-launch-moves/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_23584" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-23584" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2pABRKd"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-23584" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_KSC-20240227-PH-SPX01_0012.jpg" alt="The SpaceX Crew-8 members (from left) Alexander Grebenkin, Mike Barratt, Matthew Dominick, and Jeanette Epps are pictured in their pressure suits at the launch pad at Kennedy Space Center. Credit: SpaceX" width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_KSC-20240227-PH-SPX01_0012.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_KSC-20240227-PH-SPX01_0012-300x169.jpg 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_KSC-20240227-PH-SPX01_0012-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-23584" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The SpaceX Crew-8 members (from left) Alexander Grebenkin, Mike Barratt, Matthew Dominick, and Jeanette Epps are pictured in their pressure suits at the launch pad at Kennedy Space Center. Credit: SpaceX&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-70/"&gt;Expedition 70&lt;/a&gt; crew members will wait one more day to welcome the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; mission due to unfavorable weather conditions forecasted at launch time. Meanwhile, the seven &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/cupola/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents stayed busy Thursday on orbital maintenance tasks while planning for the upcoming departure of four crewmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SpaceX Dragon “Endeavour” spacecraft is now targeted to launch at 11:16 p.m. EST Saturday, March 2. Crew-8 Commander Matthew Dominick, Pilot Mike Barratt, and Mission Specialists Jeanette Epps and Alexander Grebenkin will take a short, automated trip to the station aboard Dragon and dock to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port at 2:15 p.m. on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dragon and station hatches will open less than two hours later and the Crew-8 members will enter the Harmony module where the Expedition 70 septet will greet them. Shortly after that, the 11 astronauts and cosmonauts will call down to Earth to share welcome remarks with mission officials and family members. The Crew-8 foursome will officially become space station flight engineers beginning a six-month research mission aboard the orbital lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on the space station, lab maintenance topped the schedule on Thursday ensuring the orbital outpost remains in tip-top shape. The station crew also had time for some science work while also training to depart aboard the SpaceX Dragon “Endurance” spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ohara-l.pdf#_blank"&gt;Loral O’Hara&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/moghbeli-j.pdf#_blank"&gt;Jasmin Moghbeli&lt;/a&gt; finalized air conditioning work inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt;. They completed swapping components on the Common Cabin Air Assembly, a life support device that circulates, cools, and dehumidifies the station’s air. Afterward, they stowed tools and packed the obsolete gear for return to Earth. O’Hara then moved on and processed fiber optic samples being produced inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=341"&gt;Microgravity Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, Moghbeli joined her Crew-7 crewmates &lt;a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Human_and_Robotic_Exploration/Astronauts/Andreas_Mogensen"&gt;Andreas Mogensen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://humans-in-space.jaxa.jp/en/astronaut/furukawa-satoshi/"&gt;Satoshi Furukawa&lt;/a&gt;, and Konstantin Borisov and prepared their return to Earth about a week after the Crew-8 mission arrives. The Crew-7 quartet practiced Dragon undocking procedures on computer tablets inside the spacecraft. The four crewmates also tried on a specialized garment that may ease their adjustment to Earth’s gravity after living for six months in weightlessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the day, Mogensen cleaned his crew quarters inside Harmony then called down to Earth for a conference with mission managers from ESA (European Space Agency). Furukawa from JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) organized emergency equipment to get ready for the Crew-8 mission. Borisov studied spacecraft and robotic piloting techniques future crews may use on planetary missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonauts Oleg Kononenko and Nikolai Chub began their morning reviewing procedures for an experiment to measure the aerodynamic forces the station experiences while orbiting Earth. The duo from Roscosmos then spent the rest of the day working inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt; continuing to assemble cargo containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/29/maintenance-day-aboard-station-as-crew-8-launch-moves/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/02/blog_KSC-20240227-PH-SPX01_0012.jpg" alt="Maintenance Day Aboard Station as Crew-8 Launch Moves"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/02/29/maintenance-day-aboard-station-as-crew-8-launch-moves/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orbital Plumbing, Foam Physics Wrap Week as Crew-8 Nears Launch</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/01/orbital-plumbing-foam-physics-wrap-week-as-crew-8-nears-launch/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/01/orbital-plumbing-foam-physics-wrap-week-as-crew-8-nears-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_23589" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-23589" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2pB5WPT"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-23589 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/03/blog_iss070e103599.jpg" alt="The SpaceX Dragon &amp;quot;Endurance&amp;quot; spacecraft, circular star trails, and Earth's atmospheric glow are pictured as the station orbited 263 miles above the north Atlantic Ocean." width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/03/blog_iss070e103599.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/03/blog_iss070e103599-300x169.jpg 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/03/blog_iss070e103599-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-23589" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The SpaceX Dragon “Endurance” spacecraft, circular star trails, and Earth’s atmospheric glow are pictured as the station orbited 263 miles above the north Atlantic Ocean.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More lab maintenance was on deck for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-70/"&gt;Expedition 70&lt;/a&gt; crew as they worked on orbital plumbing and cleaned crew quarters throughout Friday. The seven orbital residents aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; also serviced a variety of science and electronics hardware while continuing to focus on the upcoming Commercial Crew swap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ohara-l.pdf#_blank"&gt;Loral O’Hara&lt;/a&gt; spent most of her day inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt; swapping out advanced hydraulic components inside the orbital outpost’s restroom, also known as the Waste and Hygiene Compartment. She was assisted by astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Human_and_Robotic_Exploration/Astronauts/Andreas_Mogensen"&gt;Andreas Mogensen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/moghbeli-j.pdf#_blank"&gt;Jasmin Moghbeli&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://humans-in-space.jaxa.jp/en/astronaut/furukawa-satoshi/"&gt;Satoshi Furukawa&lt;/a&gt; helping uninstall then reinstall the station’s toilet returning it to operational status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moghbeli from NASA wrapped up her day cleaning her crew quarters inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier, Furukawa from JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) cleaned his crew quarters on the opposite side of Harmony from Moghbeli’s. The duo each spent about two-and-a-half hours cleaning the quarters’ vents, fans, air ducts, and sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mogensen of ESA (European Space Agency) began his shift in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; processing samples for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=7934"&gt;foam physics study&lt;/a&gt; potentially revealing phenomena not possible in Earth’s gravity. The experiment takes place inside Columbus’ &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=258"&gt;Fluid Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; and explores the coarsening and coalescing of foams that may improve fire safety, water cleaning, and other space and Earthbound applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mogensen, Moghbeli, and Furukawa, along with cosmonaut Konstantin Borisov, also continued packing personal items and station hardware throughout the day ahead of their upcoming departure aboard the SpaceX Dragon “Endurance” spacecraft. The quartet is planned to undock from the Harmony module’s space-facing port about a week after the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; mission arrives aboard the SpaceX Dragon “Endeavour” spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crew-8 is targeting its liftoff for 11:16 p.m. EST on Saturday from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center. The Commercial Crew quartet, with Commander Matthew Dominick, Pilot Mike Barratt, and Mission Specialists Jeanette Epps and Alexander Grebenkin, is due to arrive at the station at 2:15 p.m. on Sunday for an automated docking to Harmony’s forward port. The foursome will become station flight engineers living and working in space for a six-month research mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the station’s Roscosmos segment, Borisov and fellow cosmonaut Nikolai Chub tried on a unique suit being tested for its ability to draw fluids pooled in a crew member’s upper body toward the legs and feet. Space-caused fluid shifts toward the upper body are known to create eye and head pressure, as well as the more familiar space condition known as “puffy-face.” Balancing body fluids in space may also help a crew member’s heart rate and blood pressure adjust more quickly to the return to Earth’s gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chub later joined veteran cosmonaut Oleg Kononenko testing video cameras being downlinked to mission controllers on Earth. The duo also familiarized themselves with hardware that measures the aerodynamic forces the station experiences while orbiting Earth and when spaceships dock and undock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/01/orbital-plumbing-foam-physics-wrap-week-as-crew-8-nears-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/03/blog_iss070e103599.jpg" alt="Orbital Plumbing, Foam Physics Wrap Week as Crew-8 Nears Launch"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/01/orbital-plumbing-foam-physics-wrap-week-as-crew-8-nears-launch/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 Mission Coverage is Underway!</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission-coverage-is-underway/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission-coverage-is-underway/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_150" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-150" style="width: 2560px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-150" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/wp-content/uploads/sites/377/2024/03/53562175590_9a370efd44_o-scaled.jpg" alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket with the company's Dragon spacecraft on top is seen at sunset on the launch pad at Launch Complex 39A on Wednesday, Feb. 28, 2024, as preparations continue for NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 mission at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida. The eighth crew rotation mission with SpaceX and the ninth flight of Dragon with people as part of the agency’s Commercial Crew Program is slated to carry NASA astronauts Matthew Dominick, Michael Barratt, and Jeanette Epps, and Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin to the International Space Station from Launch Complex 39A at 11:16 p.m. EST on Saturday, March 2." width="2560" height="1707"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-150" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket with the company’s Dragon spacecraft on top is seen on the launch pad at Launch Complex 39A at Kennedy Space Center on Wednesday, Feb. 28, 2024. Photo credit: SpaceX&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good evening and welcome to live coverage of NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 mission – the eighth crew rotation flight and the ninth human spaceflight mission on SpaceX’s Dragon spacecraft to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; for NASA’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/commercial-space/commercial-crew-program/"&gt;Commercial Crew Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch weather officers from the U.S. Space’s Force 45th Weather Squadron predict a 40% chance of favorable weather conditions at the launch pad for liftoff. The primary weather concerns for the launch area are flight through precipitation and the thick cloud cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch is scheduled for 11:16 p.m. EST on Saturday, March 2, from Launch Complex 39A at the agency’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here at Kennedy, a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket, topped by the company’s Dragon spacecraft, named Endeavour, awaits liftoff just after midnight. NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt;, commander; &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/michael-reed-barratt/"&gt;Michael Barratt&lt;/a&gt;, pilot; &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt;, mission specialist; along with Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin, mission specialist, will fly to the space station aboard Dragon, which previously flew NASA’s SpaceX Demo Mission-2, Crew-2 and Crew-6, in addition to Axiom Mission 1, the first commercial astronaut mission to the microgravity laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The countdown is proceeding according to schedule. At Kennedy’s Neil A. Armstrong Operations and Checkout Building, the astronauts have eaten and will undergo medical checks and get a final weather briefing before suiting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting at 7:15 p.m. EST, on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;, NASA Television, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/apps/"&gt;NASA app&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NASA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and the agency’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; there will be continuous live coverage of important Crew-8 activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay with us as the countdown continues. We’ll keep you updated on the key milestones throughout this mission. Details about the mission and NASA’s Commercial Crew Program can be found by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;Crew-8 blog&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/"&gt;commercial crew blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/commercial_crew"&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NASACommercialCrew"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission-coverage-is-underway/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/wp-content/uploads/sites/377/2024/03/53562175590_9a370efd44_o-scaled.jpg" alt="NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 Mission Coverage is Underway!"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission-coverage-is-underway/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Look at Key Milestones for NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 Mission</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/a-look-at-key-milestones-for-nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/a-look-at-key-milestones-for-nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_154" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-154" style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-154" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/wp-content/uploads/sites/377/2024/03/crew-8-pad-2.jpg" alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket with the company’s Dragon spacecraft on top is seen on the launch pad at Launch Complex 39A at Kennedy Space Center. " width="1280" height="720"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-154" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket with the company’s Dragon spacecraft on top is seen on the launch pad ahead of launch from Launch Complex 39A at Kennedy Space Center. Photo credit: NASA Television&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are some of the key milestones leading up to the launch of NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 mission, as well as some critical events that occur after liftoff. The SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon spacecraft are scheduled to lift off a little more than four hours from now at 11:16 p.m. EST from Kennedy Space Center’s historic Launch Complex 39A in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Event&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;All times approximate&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
6:56 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew weather brief&lt;br&gt;
7:11 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew handoff to SpaceX&lt;br&gt;
7:16 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Suit donning and checkouts&lt;br&gt;
7:56 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew walkout from Neil A. Armstrong Operations &amp;amp; Checkout Building&lt;br&gt;
8:01 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew transportation to Launch Complex 39A&lt;br&gt;
8:21 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew arrives at pad and ascends tower&lt;br&gt;
8:41 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew ingress&lt;br&gt;
8:46 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Communication check&lt;br&gt;
8:47 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Seat rotation&lt;br&gt;
8:48 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Suit leak checks&lt;br&gt;
9:21 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Hatch close&lt;br&gt;
10:31 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; SpaceX Launch Director verifies go for propellant load&lt;br&gt;
10:34 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Crew access arm retracts&lt;br&gt;
10:37 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Dragon’s launch escape system is armed&lt;br&gt;
10:41 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; RP-1 (rocket grade kerosene) loading begins&lt;br&gt;
10:41 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st stage LOX (liquid oxygen) loading begins&lt;br&gt;
11:00 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 2nd stage LOX loading begins&lt;br&gt;
11:09 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Falcon 9 begins engine chill prior to launch&lt;br&gt;
11:11 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Dragon transitions to internal power&lt;br&gt;
11:15 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Command flight computer to begin final prelaunch checks&lt;br&gt;
11:15 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Propellant tank pressurization to flight pressure begins&lt;br&gt;
11:15 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; SpaceX Launch Director verifies go for launch&lt;br&gt;
11:16 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Falcon 9 liftoff&lt;br&gt;
11:17 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Max Q (moment of peak mechanical stress on the rocket)&lt;br&gt;
11:18 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st stage main engine cutoff (MECO)&lt;br&gt;
11:18 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st and 2nd stages separate&lt;br&gt;
11:18 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 2nd stage engine starts&lt;br&gt;
11:19 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Boostback Burn Starts&lt;br&gt;
11:22 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Boostback Burn Ends&lt;br&gt;
11:22 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st stage entry burn starts&lt;br&gt;
11:23 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st stage entry burn ends&lt;br&gt;
11:23 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st stage landing burn starts&lt;br&gt;
11:23 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 1st stage landing&lt;br&gt;
11:25 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 2nd stage engine cutoff (SECO-1)&lt;br&gt;
11:28 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Dragon separates from 2nd stage&lt;br&gt;
11:29 p.m.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Dragon nosecone open sequence begins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA’s live coverage of the Crew-8 launch is airing now on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;, NASA Television, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/apps/"&gt;NASA app&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NASA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and the agency’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and you can follow along on the mission &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/"&gt;commercial crew blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/commercial_crew"&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NASACommercialCrew"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for continuous coverage of important Crew-8 launch activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/a-look-at-key-milestones-for-nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/wp-content/uploads/sites/377/2024/03/crew-8-pad-2.jpg" alt="A Look at Key Milestones for NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 Mission"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/a-look-at-key-milestones-for-nasas-spacex-crew-8-mission/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 Suits Up for Launch</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-suits-up-for-launch/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-suits-up-for-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure id="attachment_45" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45" style="width: 1920px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-45" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/wp-content/uploads/sites/377/2024/02/KSC-20240112-PH-SPX01_0002large.jpg" alt="One Russian cosmonaust and three astronauts, three men and one woman, stand next to each other to pose for a photo." width="1920" height="1280"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-45" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Members of NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 from right to left, NASA astronauts Jeanette Epps, mission specialist; Matthew Dominick, commander; Michael Barratt, pilot; and Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin, mission specialist. Photo credit: SpaceX&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 mission NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt;, commander; &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/michael-reed-barratt/"&gt;Michael Barratt&lt;/a&gt;, pilot; and mission specialist &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt;, as well as Roscosmos cosmonaut mission specialist Alexander Grebenkin, are in the suit room in the astronaut crew quarters inside Kennedy Space Center’s Neil A. Armstrong Operations and Checkout Building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team of SpaceX suit technicians will help them as they put on their custom-fitted spacesuits and check for leaks. Designed for safety and functionality, the spacesuits supply pressurization, protecting the crew from potential depressurization, and a port located on the thigh connects to life support systems, including air and power. Also included in the suits are touchscreen-compatible gloves and a flame-resistant outer layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch now on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;, NASA Television, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/apps/"&gt;NASA app&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NASA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and the agency’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, where NASA is providing live coverage of key milestones leading up to launch and through ascent following liftoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-suits-up-for-launch/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/wp-content/uploads/sites/377/2024/02/KSC-20240112-PH-SPX01_0002large.jpg" alt="NASA’s SpaceX Crew-8 Suits Up for Launch"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasas-spacex-crew-8-suits-up-for-launch/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA, SpaceX Target Crew-8 Launch for Sunday, March 3 on Weather Concerns</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasa-spacex-target-crew-8-launch-for-sunday-march-on-weather-concerns/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;div class="at-above-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasa-spacex-target-crew-8-launch-for-sunday-march-on-weather-concerns/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;NASA and SpaceX now are targeting 10:53 p.m. EST Sunday, March 3, for the launch of the agency’s Crew-8 mission to the International Space Station from Launch Complex 39A at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida. The launch attempt March 2 was postponed due to unfavorable conditions in the flight path of the SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA will provide coverage beginning at 6:45 p.m.,&amp;nbsp;March 3, of the upcoming launch activities for the agency’s SpaceX Crew-8 mission with astronauts to the International Space Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Crew-8 launch will carry NASA astronauts Matthew Dominick, Michael Barratt, and Jeanette Epps, as well as Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin to the orbital laboratory. The targeted docking time is about 3 a.m. on Tuesday, March 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA’s mission coverage is as follows (all times Eastern and subject to change based on real-time operations):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, March 3:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;6:45 p.m. – Launch coverage begins&lt;br&gt;
10:53 p.m. – Launch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following conclusion of launch and ascent coverage, NASA coverage will continue with &lt;a class="fui-Link ___1rxvrpe f2hkw1w f3rmtva f1ewtqcl fyind8e f1k6fduh f1w7gpdv fk6fouc fjoy568 figsok6 f1hu3pq6 f11qmguv f19f4twv f1tyq0we f1g0x7ka fhxju0i f1qch9an f1cnd47f fqv5qza f1vmzxwi f1o700av f13mvf36 f1cmlufx f9n3di6 f1ids18y f1tx3yz7 f1deo86v f1eh06m1 f1iescvh fhgqx19 f1olyrje f1p93eir f1nev41a f1h8hb77 f1lqvz6u f10aw75t fsle3fq f17ae5zn" title="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3a%2f%2fwww.youtube.com%2fwatch%3fv%3dxaiee-qtoem&amp;amp;data=05%7c02%7csteven.p.siceloff%40nasa.gov%7cf92aad226b61415d8a1c08dc3b20c912%7c7005d45845be48ae8140d43da96dd17b%7c0%7c0%7c638450259193906606%7cunknown%7ctwfpbgzsb3d8eyjwijoimc4wljawmdailcjqijoiv2lumziilcjbtii6ik1hawwilcjxvci6mn0%3d%7c0%7c%7c%7c&amp;amp;sdata=iily5evpcmggf9xehamhjfgr8cbbprhz%2bbyefqvocrs%3d&amp;amp;reserved=0" href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DxAieE-QtOeM&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Csteven.p.siceloff%40nasa.gov%7Cf92aad226b61415d8a1c08dc3b20c912%7C7005d45845be48ae8140d43da96dd17b%7C0%7C0%7C638450259193906606%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=iily5EvPCmggf9XeHaMhJFgR8cbBPRhZ%2BByeFQvOCRs%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Link audio only"&gt;audio only&lt;/a&gt;, with full coverage resuming at the start of the rendezvous and docking broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Television will resume continuous mission coverage prior to docking and continue through hatch open and the welcome ceremony. For NASA TV downlink information, schedules, and links to streaming video, visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a class="fui-Link ___1rxvrpe f2hkw1w f3rmtva f1ewtqcl fyind8e f1k6fduh f1w7gpdv fk6fouc fjoy568 figsok6 f1hu3pq6 f11qmguv f19f4twv f1tyq0we f1g0x7ka fhxju0i f1qch9an f1cnd47f fqv5qza f1vmzxwi f1o700av f13mvf36 f1cmlufx f9n3di6 f1ids18y f1tx3yz7 f1deo86v f1eh06m1 f1iescvh fhgqx19 f1olyrje f1p93eir f1nev41a f1h8hb77 f1lqvz6u f10aw75t fsle3fq f17ae5zn" title="https://www.nasa.gov/nasatv/" href="https://www.nasa.gov/nasatv/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Link https://www.nasa.gov/nasatv/"&gt;https://www.nasa.gov/nasatv/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12:30 a.m. (approximately) – Postlaunch news conference on NASA TV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Stich, manager, Commercial Crew Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joel Montalbano, manager, International Space Station Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Walker, director, Dragon Mission Management, SpaceX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, March 5:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;1 a.m. – NASA TV arrival coverage begins&lt;br&gt;
3 a.m. – Targeted docking to the forward-facing port of the station’s Harmony module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatch opening will be approximately 1 hour and 45&amp;nbsp;minutes after docking followed by welcome remarks aboard station. All times are estimates and could be adjusted based on operations after launch. Follow the space station blog for the most up-to-date operations information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about the Crew-8 mission can be found by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="fui-Link ___1rxvrpe f2hkw1w f3rmtva f1ewtqcl fyind8e f1k6fduh f1w7gpdv fk6fouc fjoy568 figsok6 f1hu3pq6 f11qmguv f19f4twv f1tyq0we f1g0x7ka fhxju0i f1qch9an f1cnd47f fqv5qza f1vmzxwi f1o700av f13mvf36 f1cmlufx f9n3di6 f1ids18y f1tx3yz7 f1deo86v f1eh06m1 f1iescvh fhgqx19 f1olyrje f1p93eir f1nev41a f1h8hb77 f1lqvz6u f10aw75t fsle3fq f17ae5zn" title="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-8/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Link Crew-8"&gt;Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; blog, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="fui-Link ___1rxvrpe f2hkw1w f3rmtva f1ewtqcl fyind8e f1k6fduh f1w7gpdv fk6fouc fjoy568 figsok6 f1hu3pq6 f11qmguv f19f4twv f1tyq0we f1g0x7ka fhxju0i f1qch9an f1cnd47f fqv5qza f1vmzxwi f1o700av f13mvf36 f1cmlufx f9n3di6 f1ids18y f1tx3yz7 f1deo86v f1eh06m1 f1iescvh fhgqx19 f1olyrje f1p93eir f1nev41a f1h8hb77 f1lqvz6u f10aw75t fsle3fq f17ae5zn" title="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Link commercial crew blog"&gt;commercial crew blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="fui-Link ___1rxvrpe f2hkw1w f3rmtva f1ewtqcl fyind8e f1k6fduh f1w7gpdv fk6fouc fjoy568 figsok6 f1hu3pq6 f11qmguv f19f4twv f1tyq0we f1g0x7ka fhxju0i f1qch9an f1cnd47f fqv5qza f1vmzxwi f1o700av f13mvf36 f1cmlufx f9n3di6 f1ids18y f1tx3yz7 f1deo86v f1eh06m1 f1iescvh fhgqx19 f1olyrje f1p93eir f1nev41a f1h8hb77 f1lqvz6u f10aw75t fsle3fq f17ae5zn" title="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3a%2f%2ftwitter.com%2fcommercial_crew&amp;amp;data=05%7c02%7csteven.p.siceloff%40nasa.gov%7cf92aad226b61415d8a1c08dc3b20c912%7c7005d45845be48ae8140d43da96dd17b%7c0%7c0%7c638450259193916205%7cunknown%7ctwfpbgzsb3d8eyjwijoimc4wljawmdailcjqijoiv2lumziilcjbtii6ik1hawwilcjxvci6mn0%3d%7c0%7c%7c%7c&amp;amp;sdata=aeqzbjj%2btu6pbyk551pvn15gtef2fz6u0cuatnxg2om%3d&amp;amp;reserved=0" href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fcommercial_crew&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Csteven.p.siceloff%40nasa.gov%7Cf92aad226b61415d8a1c08dc3b20c912%7C7005d45845be48ae8140d43da96dd17b%7C0%7C0%7C638450259193916205%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=AeqZBJJ%2BTU6pbyk551pVn15gTEf2fz6u0cuatNxG2oM%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Link @commercial_crew"&gt;@commercial_crew&lt;/a&gt; on X, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="fui-Link ___1rxvrpe f2hkw1w f3rmtva f1ewtqcl fyind8e f1k6fduh f1w7gpdv fk6fouc fjoy568 figsok6 f1hu3pq6 f11qmguv f19f4twv f1tyq0we f1g0x7ka fhxju0i f1qch9an f1cnd47f fqv5qza f1vmzxwi f1o700av f13mvf36 f1cmlufx f9n3di6 f1ids18y f1tx3yz7 f1deo86v f1eh06m1 f1iescvh fhgqx19 f1olyrje f1p93eir f1nev41a f1h8hb77 f1lqvz6u f10aw75t fsle3fq f17ae5zn" title="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3a%2f%2fwww.facebook.com%2fnasacommercialcrew&amp;amp;data=05%7c02%7csteven.p.siceloff%40nasa.gov%7cf92aad226b61415d8a1c08dc3b20c912%7c7005d45845be48ae8140d43da96dd17b%7c0%7c0%7c638450259193922781%7cunknown%7ctwfpbgzsb3d8eyjwijoimc4wljawmdailcjqijoiv2lumziilcjbtii6ik1hawwilcjxvci6mn0%3d%7c0%7c%7c%7c&amp;amp;sdata=tre4%2bx6hkfzs21g6qf6dvo3zoc%2bz8an%2fa1x0leaky3a%3d&amp;amp;reserved=0" href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FNASACommercialCrew&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Csteven.p.siceloff%40nasa.gov%7Cf92aad226b61415d8a1c08dc3b20c912%7C7005d45845be48ae8140d43da96dd17b%7C0%7C0%7C638450259193922781%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=TRE4%2BX6hKfZs21G6Qf6Dvo3zoc%2Bz8An%2Fa1X0lEAky3A%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Link commercial crew"&gt;commercial crew&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --&gt;&lt;div class="at-below-post-homepage addthis_tool" data-url="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasa-spacex-target-crew-8-launch-for-sunday-march-on-weather-concerns/"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content --&gt;	</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/02/nasa-spacex-target-crew-8-launch-for-sunday-march-on-weather-concerns/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
