<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NASA Space Station Blog</title>
    <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/</link>
    <description>The official blog of NASA's space station news.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 04:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Science Hardware Work Completes Week; NASA Managers Discuss Crew Flight Test</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/23/science-hardware-work-completes-week-nasa-managers-discuss-crew-flight-test/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25015" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25015" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qbxK2P"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25015" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e513842_439a27.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams, Boeing's Crew Flight Test Commander and Pilot respectively, inspect safety hardware aboard the space station." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e513842_439a27.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e513842_439a27.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e513842_439a27.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25015" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams, Boeing’s Crew Flight Test Commander and Pilot respectively, inspect safety hardware aboard the space station.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced research hardware work took precedence aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; at the end of the week as the crew readied satellite gear and experimental communications components for placement in the vacuum of space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; spent Friday installing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=883"&gt;Small Satellite Orbital Deployer&lt;/a&gt; onto the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s multipurpose experiment platform (MPEP). He then loaded the MPEP into Kibo’s airlock where JAXA’s (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) robotic arm will grapple the device and position it away from the space station to release a series of CubeSats into Earth orbit for a variety of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/#q=%22j-ssod%22&amp;amp;i=71&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a=?"&gt;educational and research activities&lt;/a&gt;. NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt;, Pilot for &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/boeing-crew-flight-test"&gt;Boeing’s Crew Flight Test&lt;/a&gt;, assisted Dominick throughout the day and familiarized herself with CubeSat operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt;, Expedition 71 Flight Engineer, and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;, Crew Flight Test Commander, configured the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2020/12/21/new-science-airlock-expands-stations-research-capacity/"&gt;NanoRacks Bishop airlock&lt;/a&gt; that will soon open up to the external microgravity environment. Earlier, NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; helped Barratt install the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9185"&gt;ArgUS multi-payload carrier&lt;/a&gt; inside Bishop. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; will grapple Bishop with the ArgUS payload inside for installation on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7799"&gt;Bartolomeo&lt;/a&gt; external research platform for a satellite communications study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/station/commercial-crew/nasa-astronauts-wilmore-williams-space-station-science-highlights/"&gt;Find out more and see what Wilmore and Williams have been up to during their stay aboard the orbiting laboratory.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; spent her entire shift on Friday conducting lab maintenance. She started the morning reorganizing cargo stowed in Kibo. After lunch, she inspected rack hardware throughout the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/destiny-laboratory-module/"&gt;Destiny&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/unity-module/"&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt;, and Tranquility modules, including the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of the day, she swapped out a tank and a hose and on the orbital lab’s restroom, also known as the waste and hygiene compartment, located in Tranquility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonauts Oleg Kononenko and Nikolai Chub partnered Friday morning on inspections and hardware replacements in the aft end of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;. Kononenko also cleaned ventilation systems while Chub researched futuristic planetary and robotic piloting techniques. Roscosmos Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin downloaded data collected from a radiation detector then worked inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/tag/nauka/"&gt;Nauka science module&lt;/a&gt; checking its ventilation hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Administrator Bill Nelson and leadership will hold an internal Agency Test Flight Readiness Review on Saturday, Aug. 24, for NASA’s Boeing Crew Flight Test. Afterward, NASA will host a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/leadership-to-discuss-nasas-boeing-crew-flight-test/"&gt;news conference at 1 p.m. EDT&lt;/a&gt; from the agency’s Johnson Space Center in Houston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e513842_439a27.jpg" alt="Science Hardware Work Completes Week; NASA Managers Discuss Crew Flight Test"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/23/science-hardware-work-completes-week-nasa-managers-discuss-crew-flight-test/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monday Sees Physical Science Prep and Training for Station Crew</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/26/monday-sees-physical-science-prep-and-training-for-station-crew/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25020" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25020" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2q3z1zm"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25020" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg" alt=" Boeing's Starliner spacecraft that launched NASA's Crew Flight Test astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams to the International Space Station is pictured docked to the Harmony module's forward port. This long-duration photograph was taken at night from the orbital complex as it soared 258 miles above western China." width="840" height="560" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg 8256w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg?resize=1024,683 1024w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25020" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Boeing’s Starliner spacecraft that launched NASA’s Crew Flight Test astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams to the International Space Station is pictured docked to the Harmony module’s forward port. This long-duration photograph was taken at night from the orbital complex as it soared 258 miles above western China.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A suite of training and conferences kept the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents busy on Monday as they embark on a new week of work in microgravity. Though a light duty science day, some crew members did schedule in time to assess how spaceflight affects the human body and prep for upcoming physical science investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; set up hardware for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/hrp/cipher/"&gt;CIPHER&lt;/a&gt; investigation and then conducted an exam on NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt; to assess how microgravity affects the vestibular system, including spatial orientation, cognitive function, and changes in head-eye coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; spent some time in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt; troubleshooting the toilet pressure sensor, then replaced experiment samples and igniter tips in &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2060"&gt;SoFIE&lt;/a&gt;, a physical science payload used to study the ignition and flammability of spacecraft materials. Meanwhile, NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; spent some time replacing &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=1037"&gt;Packed Bed Retractor Experiment&lt;/a&gt; hardware, another physical science investigation that looks at the behaviors of gases and liquids in microgravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/boeing-crew-flight-test/"&gt;Boeing Crew Flight Test&lt;/a&gt; Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and Pilot &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; spent Monday powering up communication software and holding a conference with ground teams as they begin their formal integration into the Expedition 71/72 crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA announced on Saturday that Boeing’s Starliner spacecraft will &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-decides-to-bring-starliner-spacecraft-back-to-earth-without-crew/"&gt;return to Earth uncrewed&lt;/a&gt;, allowing the agency and Boeing to continue gathering testing data on Starliner during its upcoming flight home, while also not accepting more risk than necessary for its crew. Wilmore and Williams will continue their work aboard the orbiting laboratory through February 2025 and fly home aboard a Dragon spacecraft with two other crew members assigned to the agency’s SpaceX Crew-9 mission. Starliner is expected to depart from the space station and make a safe, controlled autonomous re-entry and landing in early September. Since their arrival, the duo has been supporting &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/station/commercial-crew/nasa-astronauts-wilmore-williams-space-station-science-highlights/"&gt;station research&lt;/a&gt;, maintenance, Starliner system testing, and a host of other orbital activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare for upcoming missions in September, Barratt, Epps, Dyson, Dominick, Wilmore, and Williams, along with cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin, all completed a round of SpaceX Dragon overview training throughout the day. The septet then joined forces in the evening to review Dragon emergency procedures and hold a conference with ground teams to discuss future Dragon configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, the septet was joined by station Commander Oleg Kononenko and Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub of Roscosmos to discuss emergency response and coordination amongst all crew members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kononenko and Chub also partnered throughout the day to inspect and replace hardware in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda&lt;/a&gt; service module and install software to a few station computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soyuz MS-26 prime and backup crew members flew to their launch site in Baikonur, Kazakhstan to begin final prelaunch training ahead of the launch of NASA astronaut Don Pettit and Roscosmos cosmonauts Alexei Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner, currently scheduled for Wednesday, Sept. 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt; on X, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly updates from NASA Johnson Space Center at: &lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here: &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/53850328598_513c2158ce_o.jpg" alt="Monday Sees Physical Science Prep and Training for Station Crew"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/26/monday-sees-physical-science-prep-and-training-for-station-crew/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Botany, Eye Research, Plasma Physics Fill Science Schedule on Station</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/27/space-botany-eye-research-plasma-physics-fill-science-schedule-on-station/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25033" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25033" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25033 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547724b.jpg" alt="Astronaut Tracy C. Dyson smiles for a portrait in the vestibule between the Kibo laboratory module and the Harmony module." width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547724b.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547724b.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547724b.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25033" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Tracy C. Dyson smiles for a portrait in the vestibule between the Kibo laboratory module and the Harmony module.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was a science-packed day aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; as the astronauts and cosmonauts explored space botany, eye health, and plasma physics to promote longer spaceflights farther away from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-71/"&gt;Expedition 71&lt;/a&gt; took turns tending to plants growing inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=374"&gt;Veggie&lt;/a&gt; space botany facility throughout the day. Barratt started first scanning leaves on &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8812"&gt;two types of grasses&lt;/a&gt; using an agricultural multispectral device measuring leaf thickness, chlorophyll, and other plant properties. Epps followed and photographed the plants so scientists on the ground could analyze the space-grown grasses. Results from the botany experiment may show space-caused changes to photosynthesis and plant metabolism and possibly inform bioregenerative life support systems on future spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, Epps peered into the eyes of NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; using standard medical imaging gear found in a doctor’s office on Earth. She was specifically looking at his optic nerve with real-time assistance from researchers on the ground. NASA scientists are trying to determine if &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8872"&gt;genetics and a B vitamin condition&lt;/a&gt; could affect crew vision in space and develop countermeasures to prevent the swelling of the optic nerve on spaceflight missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; had a light-duty day first examining &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8937"&gt;experimental life support hardware&lt;/a&gt; installed in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=341"&gt;Microgravity Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt;. Next, she, Commander Oleg Kononenko, and Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub took turns reading characters midday on an eye chart so eye doctors could assess their visual acuity, or vision sharpness. Afterward, Dyson spent about 25 minutes testing VHF communication systems with mission controllers in the United States, Japan, Germany, and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; worked together throughout Tuesday on life support maintenance in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;. The duo uninstalled the carbon dioxide removal assembly from Tranquility’s Air Revitalization System rack then reconfigured and replaced components on the life support device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kononenko spent most of his morning swapping out computer and electronics gear in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt; before working the rest of the afternoon inspecting modules in the Roscosmos segment of the orbital outpost. Chub started his day photographing surfaces treated with a variety of disinfectants analyzing their effectiveness in microgravity then finished his shift checking Roscosmos power supply diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin dedicated his entire day to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=1192"&gt;Plasma Kristall-4&lt;/a&gt; experiment supported by both Roscosmos and ESA (European Space Agency). Grebenkin checked the pressure on argon and neon gas bottles that supply the investigation which observes complex plasmas, or ionized gases produced by high temperatures, potentially benefitting spacecraft designs and fundamental research on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547724b.jpg" alt="Space Botany, Eye Research, Plasma Physics Fill Science Schedule on Station"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/27/space-botany-eye-research-plasma-physics-fill-science-schedule-on-station/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Works Spacecraft Configurations and Eye Checks on Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/28/crew-works-spacecraft-configurations-and-eye-checks-on-wednesday/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25043" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25043" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qcovfb"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25043 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547275.jpg" alt="The last rays of an orbital sunset fade below Earth's horizon illuminating the atmosphere in this photograph from the International Space Station as it soared above the Atlantic Ocean." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547275.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547275.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547275.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25043" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The last rays of an orbital sunset fade below Earth’s horizon illuminating the atmosphere in this photograph from the International Space Station as it soared above the Atlantic Ocean.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragon spacecraft configurations topped Wednesday’s task list aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; as the orbital residents prepare for crew swap activities in September and October. Human research duties and lab maintenance tasks rounded out the day for the nine crewmates living and working on the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six astronauts worked throughout the day configuring the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/05/spacex-dragon-with-crew-8-aboard-docks-to-station/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon Endeavour&lt;/a&gt; spacecraft’s emergency systems and updating the vehicle’s emergency procedures. The NASA astronauts split up the daylong tasks as &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; worked inside the spacecraft configuring its emergency systems and computer tablets as it nears an October return to Earth with four &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; focused on updating emergency procedures including responses to unlikely events such as a depressurization, fire, or ammonia leak aboard Dragon. The trio also documented individual roles and responsibilities for the astronauts in the event of a contingency aboard Dragon after it departs the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astronauts still had time for light science tasks and lab upkeep while ensuring Dragon is prepared for its upcoming departure. Epps watered &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8812"&gt;two types of grasses&lt;/a&gt; growing inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=374"&gt;Veggie&lt;/a&gt; space botany facility. The grasses are being studied to observe space-caused changes to photosynthesis and plant metabolism and possibly inform bioregenerative life support systems on future spacecraft. Epps also drained resupply tanks and serviced orbital plumbing systems in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, Dominick examined Dyson’s eyes using standard medical imaging hardware in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;. Cosmonauts Oleg Kononenko and Nikolai Chub also participated in the regularly scheduled eye exams. Doctors on the ground remotely monitored both sessions to understand how living in weightlessness affects a crew member’s cornea, lens, and retina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kononenko and Chub kicked off their day with a cardiac study as Kononenko assisted Chub who attached sensors to himself that measured his heart rate while relaxing. The duo would then split up and work on a variety of electronics and life support systems in the station’s Roscosmos segment. Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin worked on orbital plumbing duties in the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/tag/nauka/"&gt;Nauka science module&lt;/a&gt; during the morning before spending the afternoon collecting station air samples for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e547275.jpg" alt="Crew Works Spacecraft Configurations and Eye Checks on Wednesday"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/28/crew-works-spacecraft-configurations-and-eye-checks-on-wednesday/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Busy Week of Science, Robotics, and Spacecraft Activities on Station</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/29/busy-week-of-science-robotics-and-spacecraft-activities-on-station/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25048" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25048" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qcZAYG"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25048 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e549317.jpg" alt="A waning gibbous moon sets over the Pacific Ocean as the International Space Station orbited 258 miles above." width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e549317.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e549317.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e549317.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25048" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;A waning gibbous moon sets over the Pacific Ocean as the International Space Station orbited 258 miles above.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a busy week aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; and Thursday was no exception with ongoing space research, systems maintenance, robotics activities, and an orbital reboost for an upcoming crew mission. The nine lab crewmates have been working together and coordinating closely with mission controllers from around the world ensuring safe and successful mission operations in low-Earth orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; returned to space botany on Thursday servicing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; located in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;. The duo replaced a variety of life support components and sensors inside the microgravity greenhouse that supports space-grown plants for both research and consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; began their day continuing to configure emergency systems inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/05/spacex-dragon-with-crew-8-aboard-docks-to-station/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon Endeavour&lt;/a&gt; spacecraft. Williams also partnered with NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; and updated Dragon emergency procedures. Barratt wrapped up his day inside Dragon charging computer tablet batteries and synchronizing the portable computers for satellite coverage. Dragon is due to return to Earth in early October bringing home four &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-8/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilmore and Dyson then finished the afternoon cleaning the inside of the carbon dioxide removal assembly (CDRA). Wilmore and Williams removed the CDRA from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;’s Air Revitalization System (ARS) on Tuesday beginning the weeklong maintenance job. It will be reinstalled in the ARS and reactivated early next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, robotics controllers on Earth remotely commanded the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; to remove the science packed &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2020/12/21/new-science-airlock-expands-stations-research-capacity/"&gt;NanoRacks Bishop airlock&lt;/a&gt; from Tranquility. Bishop was then maneuvered toward the Mobile Transporter where it was temporarily installed for experiment transfers. Canadarm2 then retrieved the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=8503"&gt;ArgUS multi-payload carrier&lt;/a&gt; from Bishop and installed it on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7799"&gt;Bartolomeo&lt;/a&gt; external science platform. The newly installed &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9185"&gt;radio frequency research hardware&lt;/a&gt; will demonstrate advanced satellite communications to improve aerospace systems on Earth and space. Bishop has been returned to Tranquility where it will be repressurized and opened for crew entry on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The orbital outpost’s three cosmonauts from Roscosmos also remained busy on Thursday conducting their array of life science, lab upkeep, and robotics checks. Station Commander Oleg Kononenko focused on science, first swapping samples inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1853"&gt;Electromagnetic Levitator&lt;/a&gt;, a research device that measures the thermophysical properties of liquid metallic alloys at high temperatures. Next, he attached sensors to himself measuring his heart rate while relaxing. Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub installed and tested a device that measures mass in microgravity then packed trash and discarded gear inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/06/01/cargo-craft-docks-to-station-completes-space-delivery/"&gt;Progress 88 cargo craft&lt;/a&gt;. Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin inventoried components that control the European Robotic Arm then uninstalled software that supported a plasma physics study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Space Station is soaring higher this week after the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;Progress 89 cargo craft&lt;/a&gt;, docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port, fired its thrusters for nearly 18 minutes on Tuesday. The reboost puts the space station at the correct altitude for the arrival of the Soyuz MS-26 crew ship in September. The Soyuz spacecraft, carrying NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; and Roscosmos cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner, is due to dock to the station’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/rassvet-mini-research-module/"&gt;Rassvet module&lt;/a&gt; just three hours after launching from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e549317.jpg" alt="Busy Week of Science, Robotics, and Spacecraft Activities on Station"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/29/busy-week-of-science-robotics-and-spacecraft-activities-on-station/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Botany, Combustion Physics, and Eye Checks Finish Week</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/30/space-botany-combustion-physics-and-eye-checks-finish-week/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25055" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25055" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qd3zCQ"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25055" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e580038.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts (from left) Tracy C. Dyson and Suni Williams update emergency procedure manuals aboard the space station's Columbus laboratory module." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e580038.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e580038.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e580038.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25055" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts (from left) Tracy C. Dyson and Suni Williams update emergency procedure manuals aboard the space station’s Columbus laboratory module.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space botany and combustion physics wrapped up the research schedule aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Friday. The orbital residents also finalized life support maintenance work and conducted eye exams at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; continued her weeklong plant research activities inside Kibo’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt;. She began checking carbon dioxide bottles inside the space botany habitat installed in an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=598"&gt;EXPRESS rack&lt;/a&gt;. Next, Epps refilled a water reservoir inside the plant habitat for systems testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; began her day in the Kibo laboratory module swapping out sample hardware inside the &lt;a href="https://humans-in-space.jaxa.jp/en/biz-lab/experiment/facility/pm/scem/"&gt;Solid Combustion Experiment Module&lt;/a&gt; that observes how flames spread over solid fuels. She also joined Roscosmos cosmonauts Oleg Kononenko and Nikolai Chub checking the seats inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/25/soyuz-spacecraft-docks-to-station-with-three-crew-members-aboard/"&gt;Soyuz MS-25&lt;/a&gt; crew ship the trio will ride back to Earth in late September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2020/12/21/new-science-airlock-expands-stations-research-capacity/"&gt;NanoRacks Bishop airlock&lt;/a&gt; has been robotically reattached to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt; following several days of science transfers. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/mobile-servicing-system/"&gt;Canadarm2 robotic arm&lt;/a&gt; extracted radio frequency experiment hardware from Bishop earlier this week and then installed it on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7799"&gt;Bartolomeo&lt;/a&gt; external science platform. Canadarm2 returned and attached Bishop to Tranquility where NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt; reconfigured and outfitted the science and cargo airlock for internal activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominick earlier joined Dyson in Columbus as she scanned his eyes using the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=736"&gt;Ultrasound 2&lt;/a&gt; biomedical device. Dyson was imaging Dominick’s cornea, lens, and optic nerve with real time assistance from doctors on the ground studying how living long-term in weightlessness affects crew vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; completed several days of life support work that began on Tuesday when the duo removed the carbon dioxide removal assembly (CDRA) from Tranquility’s Air Revitalization System rack. The pair have been cleaning components inside the CDRA all week wrapping up that work at the end of Friday. The CDRA will be reinstalled on Monday and returned to service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Space Station crew and ground teams have completed the configuration of the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/05/spacex-dragon-with-crew-8-aboard-docks-to-station/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon spacecraft&lt;/a&gt; supporting &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-8/"&gt;Crew-8&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to now serve as the emergency return spacecraft for NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams, if needed, until NASA’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-9/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-9&lt;/a&gt; mission arrives following launch no earlier than Sept. 24. Station emergency procedures and crew trainings have been updated to reflect this change. The Starliner spacecraft is targeting an uncrewed undocking on Friday, Sept. 6, and landing on Saturday, Sept. 7, pending weather and operational readiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander Kononenko and Flight Engineer Chub participated in their own set of eye exams at the end of Friday. The duo from Roscosmos took turns in Columbus scanning each other’s eyes with the Ultrasound 2 downlinking real time imagery of their cornea, lens, and optic nerve. Earlier, the duo began collecting cargo for return to Earth aboard the Soyuz MS-25 and serviced an oxygen generator in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;. Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin refilled coolant inside Zvezda’s air conditioning system then collected atmospheric measurements in the 24-year-old module for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/08/blog_iss071e580038.jpg" alt="Space Botany, Combustion Physics, and Eye Checks Finish Week"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/30/space-botany-combustion-physics-and-eye-checks-finish-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sounds from Starliner Speakers Traced to Audio Configuration</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/03/sounds-from-starliner-speakers-traced-to-audio-configuration/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_691" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-691" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-691" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/boeing-crew-flight-test/wp-content/uploads/sites/361/2024/06/53797943056_567624c797_o.jpg" alt="Looking down at Boeing's Starliner spacecraft attached to the International Space Station." width="840" height="1120"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-691" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Starliner spacecraft on NASA’s Boeing Crew Flight Test is pictured docked to the Harmony module’s forward port as the International Space Station orbited 263 miles above the Mediterranean Sea. Photo credit: NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pulsing sound from a speaker in Boeing’s Starliner spacecraft heard by NASA astronaut Butch Wilmore aboard the International Space Station has stopped. The feedback from the speaker was the result of an audio configuration between the space station and Starliner. The space station audio system is complex, allowing multiple spacecraft and modules to be interconnected, and it is common to experience noise and feedback. The crew is asked to contact mission control when they hear sounds originating in the comm system. The speaker feedback Wilmore reported has no technical impact to the crew, Starliner, or station operations, including Starliner’s uncrewed undocking from the station no earlier than Friday, Sept. 6.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/boeing-crew-flight-test/wp-content/uploads/sites/361/2024/06/53797943056_567624c797_o.jpg" alt="Sounds from Starliner Speakers Traced to Audio Configuration"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/03/sounds-from-starliner-speakers-traced-to-audio-configuration/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Works Human Research and U.S. Spacecraft Ops on Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/03/crew-works-human-research-and-u-s-spacecraft-ops-on-tuesday/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25066" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25066" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qcobaS"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25066" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547361.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts Matthew Dominick and Suni Williams smile for a selfie portrait aboard the International Space Station's Kibo laboratory module." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547361.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547361.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547361.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25066" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts Matthew Dominick and Suni Williams smile for a selfie portrait aboard the International Space Station’s Kibo laboratory module.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human research and U.S. spacecraft operations were the primary activities aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday. The crew is exploring how the human body adapts to microgravity while also preparing Boeing’s Starliner spacecraft for its departure at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-71/"&gt;Expedition 71&lt;/a&gt; Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; kicked off his day setting up wearable biomedical hardware then working out to understand how living in space affects the human heart and breathing. He first put on a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7392"&gt;vest and headband packed with sensors&lt;/a&gt; measuring his heart and breathing rate, blood pressure, and other health parameters. Next, he pedaled on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/destiny-laboratory-module/"&gt;Destiny laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=821"&gt;exercise cycle&lt;/a&gt; while his cardio-respiratory data was recorded to a computer. Scientists will study the results to understand how weightlessness affects a crew member’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8597"&gt;blood pressure and breathing&lt;/a&gt; and learn how to keep astronauts healthy on missions to the Moon, Mars, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominick joined fellow NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; for eye exams as personnel on the ground monitored the checks in real time. Dyson took charge as the crew medical officer operating a medical imaging device in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt; viewing her crewmates’ optic nerve, retina, and cornea. Some astronauts have reported vision issues and doctors have noted changes in eye structure that they seek to understand and counter to ensure successful long-term space expeditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space physics and life support research were also on the science schedule to help NASA and its international partners design next generation spacecraft and space habitats for lunar and planetary human missions. NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; opened up the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=317"&gt;Combustion Integrated Rack&lt;/a&gt; inside Destiny and replaced and cleaned research components for a series of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22Solid+Fuel+Ignition+and+Extinction%22&amp;amp;i=71&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;fire safety investigations&lt;/a&gt;. The experiments explore how flames spread, how materials burn, and ways to extinguish fires in microgravity to improve safety in space. Dyson swapped out test life support gear inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8937"&gt;Packed Bed Reactor Experiment&lt;/a&gt; taking place inside Destiny’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=341"&gt;Microgravity Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt;. The investigation is exploring advanced water recovery systems for crew missions in a variety of gravity scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominick and Barratt also reviewed operations procedures inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/05/spacex-dragon-with-crew-8-aboard-docks-to-station/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon Endeavour&lt;/a&gt; spacecraft ahead of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-8/"&gt;Crew-8&lt;/a&gt; departure later this month. The duo then invited NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; inside Dragon bringing the pair up-to-speed with the spacecraft’s systems and crew configuration. Wilmore and Williams will return to Earth aboard another Dragon when &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-9/"&gt;Crew-9&lt;/a&gt; ends its mission in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilmore and Williams, both veteran NASA astronauts, prepared Starliner for its weekend departure. The Starliner commander and pilot reconfigured the spacecraft’s seats for an uncrewed landing and packed cargo inside the vehicle this week for retrieval on Earth. They also returned standard visiting vehicle emergency hardware stowed inside Starliner back to the station for future mission operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starliner is due to end its stay at the orbital outpost at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-sets-coverage-for-starliner-news-conference-return-to-earth/"&gt;6:04 p.m. EDT on Friday&lt;/a&gt; and undock from Harmony’s forward port. The uncrewed spacecraft from Boeing will return to Earth and land in New Mexico about six hours later. Undocking coverage begins at 5:45 p.m. Friday on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-boeing-crew-flight-test-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/apps/"&gt;NASA app&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NASA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and the agency’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://nasa.gov/nasatv"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Roscosmos segment of the orbital outpost, station Commander Oleg Kononenko checked power generation and life support systems then set up Earth observation hardware to image the atmosphere in infrared and visible spectral ranges. Flight Engineers Nikolai Chub and Alexander Grebenkin joined each other and tested an &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/ISS_Science_Blog/2015/06/02/rubber-vacuum-pants-that-suck/"&gt;anti-gravity suit&lt;/a&gt; for its ability to counter the effects of weightless on the human body and help crews adjust quicker to the return to Earth’s gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547361.jpg" alt="Crew Works Human Research and U.S. Spacecraft Ops on Tuesday"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/03/crew-works-human-research-and-u-s-spacecraft-ops-on-tuesday/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Studies Space Effects on Humans, Prepares Spaceships for Departure</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/04/crew-studies-space-effects-on-humans-prepares-spaceships-for-departure/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25071" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25071" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qcXj87"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25071" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547091.jpg" alt="Stars glitter above a yellow-green atmospheric glow crowning Earth's horizon nn this long-duration shot taken by NASA astronaut Jeanette Epps." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547091.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547091.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547091.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25071" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Stars glitter above a yellow-green atmospheric glow crowning Earth’s horizon nn this long-duration shot taken by NASA astronaut Jeanette Epps.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, the crew aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; continued researching ways to protect the human body from the effects of spaceflight and packed a pair of spaceships for return to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One common symptom of living in space is called “puffy face” and is the result of body fluids moving toward a crew member’s head caused by living in weightlessness. NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; explored ways to prevent that phenomena that may create health issues including changes in eye structure and vision. The duo first conducted eye checks, then collected blood samples, before Dominick put on a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8984"&gt;thigh cuffs&lt;/a&gt; with assistance from Epps. The thigh cuff is being tested for its ability to reverse the space-caused headward fluid shifts. During the test, a variety of sensors, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=736"&gt;Ultrasound 2&lt;/a&gt; device, and blood pressure checks collected Dominick’s health data to determine the effectiveness of the thigh cuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; spent the day loading cargo inside the Boeing Starliner spacecraft for return to Earth. The pair removed Starliner’s crew seats, which will later be reinstalled, for better access when storing the extra cargo, then photographed and inspected the spaceship’s cabin ahead of its hatch closure scheduled for Thursday. Afterward, the veteran astronaut duo conducted a vision test reading characters off an eye chart so eye doctors could assess their visual acuity, or vision sharpness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncrewed Starliner is scheduled to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-sets-coverage-for-starliner-news-conference-return-to-earth/"&gt;6:04 p.m. EDT on Friday&lt;/a&gt; and land in New Mexico about six hours later. Undocking coverage begins at 5:45 p.m. Friday on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-boeing-crew-flight-test-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/apps/"&gt;NASA app&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NASA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and the agency’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://nasa.gov/nasatv"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Wilmore and Williams will remain aboard the orbital outpost until February when they are scheduled to return to Earth aboard the SpaceX Dragon spacecraft with the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-9/"&gt;Crew-9&lt;/a&gt; mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt; spent their day on a host of standard maintenance tasks on the orbital outpost. Dyson videotaped cable configurations in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;, collected and stowed biological samples for analysis, then swapped out orbital plumbing hardware. Barratt configured computer tablets, assisted with the Starliner cargo packing, then transferred files stored on an ultrasonic inspection device to a space station computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-71/"&gt;Expedition 71&lt;/a&gt; Commander Oleg Kononenko from Roscosmos began collecting station hardware and science gear that will soon be packed aboard the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/25/soyuz-spacecraft-docks-to-station-with-three-crew-members-aboard/"&gt;Soyuz MS-25&lt;/a&gt; crew ship docked to the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/11/26/russias-new-docking-module-arrives-at-station/"&gt;Prichal docking module&lt;/a&gt;. He, Dyson, and Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub are planning to return home aboard the Soyuz spacecraft in late September. Chub worked throughout Wednesday photographing station surfaces being treated with an experimental disinfectant then collecting air samples for microbial analysis. Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin explored futuristic piloting techniques on a computer before setting up Earth observation hardware to image Earth’s atmosphere in ultraviolet wavelengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/09/blog_iss071e547091.jpg" alt="Crew Studies Space Effects on Humans, Prepares Spaceships for Departure"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/04/crew-studies-space-effects-on-humans-prepares-spaceships-for-departure/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starliner Nears Departure, Crew Focuses on Space Research</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/05/starliner-nears-departure-crew-focuses-on-space-research/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_24778" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24778" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-24778" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/07/blog_iss071e265073_stk.jpg" alt="Boeing's Starliner spacecraft is pictured from a window on the SpaceX Dragon Endeavour spacecraft docked to the Harmony module's forward port." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/07/blog_iss071e265073_stk.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/07/blog_iss071e265073_stk.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/07/blog_iss071e265073_stk.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-24778" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Boeing’s Starliner spacecraft is pictured from a window on the SpaceX Dragon Endeavour spacecraft docked to the Harmony module’s forward port.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission managers have given the first “go” for the Boeing Starliner spacecraft to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; at 6:04 p.m. EDT on Friday and land in New Mexico about six hours later. NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; have finished packing Starliner with cargo and configuring its cabin for return. The duo closed Starliner’s hatch for the final time Thursday afternoon readying the spacecraft for its uncrewed departure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilmore and Williams will remain aboard the orbital outpost until February when they are scheduled to return to Earth aboard the SpaceX Dragon spacecraft with the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-9/"&gt;Crew-9&lt;/a&gt; mission. Starliner’s departure coverage begins at 5:45 p.m. Friday on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-boeing-crew-flight-test-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/apps/"&gt;NASA app&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NASA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and the agency’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://nasa.gov/nasatv"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, a multitude of science occurred aboard the orbital outpost on Thursday with the crew exploring microgravity’s effect on the heart and breathing, space botany, fire safety, and Earth observations. Scientists on the ground analyze the research data for unique insights on improving human health on and off the planet as well as promoting Earth and space industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-71/"&gt;Expedition 71&lt;/a&gt; Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/tracy-caldwell-dyson/"&gt;Tracy C. Dyson&lt;/a&gt; kicked off her day wearing a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7392"&gt;sensor-packed headband and vest&lt;/a&gt; while pedaling on an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=821"&gt;exercise cycle&lt;/a&gt; inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/destiny-laboratory-module/"&gt;Destiny laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;. Her cardio-respiratory data was recorded to a computer helping scientists understand how weightlessness affects a crew member’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8597"&gt;blood pressure and breathing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/michael-barratt/"&gt;Mike Barratt&lt;/a&gt; photographed and watered plants growing for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8812"&gt;C4 Photosynthesis in Space&lt;/a&gt; experiment inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=374"&gt;Veggie&lt;/a&gt; space botany facility. The investigation observes space-caused photosynthesis and plant metabolism changes in two types of grasses growing inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=598"&gt;EXPRESS Rack&lt;/a&gt;’s Veggie research device. Results may inform bioregenerative life support systems on future spacecraft and boost fundamental knowledge of botanical processes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fire safety on spacecraft is just as critical and important as fire safety on Earth. However, flames and materials burn differently in the weightless environment requiring a different approach to fire protection. Researchers are using the space station’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=317"&gt;Combustion Integrated Rack&lt;/a&gt; (CIR) to safely study flames in space to learn how to protect spacecraft and space habitats. NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/jeanette-j-epps/"&gt;Jeanette Epps&lt;/a&gt; swapped components and removed burnt samples inside the CIR for a series of experiments exploring &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22Solid+Fuel+Ignition+and+Extinction%22&amp;amp;i=71&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;space flammability and fire suppression&lt;/a&gt; in microgravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pointing his camera out a window in the cupola and toward the Moon, NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/matthew-dominick/"&gt;Matthew Dominick&lt;/a&gt; photographed light reflecting off the lunar surface illuminated from Earth, also called &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8957"&gt;earthshine&lt;/a&gt;. Measuring changes in Earth’s light reflected from the Moon may help scientists update their climate models and inform the design of future atmosphere observing satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Commander Oleg Kononenko spent his day preparing for upcoming Soyuz spacecraft operations. The five-time station resident is collecting cargo that will soon be packed in the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/03/25/soyuz-spacecraft-docks-to-station-with-three-crew-members-aboard/"&gt;Soyuz MS-25&lt;/a&gt; spacecraft for its departure in late September. Afterward, the veteran cosmonaut readied the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt; for the Sept. 11 docking of the Soyuz MS-26 crew ship bringing to the orbital lab NASA astronaut &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; and Roscosmos cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Wagner. Flight Engineers Nikolai Chub and Alexander Grebenkin split their day conducting a variety of Roscosmos research and lab maintenance tasks. Chub and Kononenko also participated in eye checks at the end of the day on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;ISS Progress 89&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port fired its thrusters at 3:45 p.m. for 13 minutes today raising the space station’s altitude. The orbital reboost is the third and final maneuver setting up the proper phasing for the arrival of the Soyuz MS-26 next week and Starliner’s undocking opportunity on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly video highlights at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/videoupdate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/07/blog_iss071e265073_stk.jpg" alt="Starliner Nears Departure, Crew Focuses on Space Research"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/09/05/starliner-nears-departure-crew-focuses-on-space-research/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
