<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NASA Space Station Blog</title>
    <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/</link>
    <description>The official blog of NASA's space station news.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 05:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Space Delivery Arrives at Station Aboard Progress Cargo Craft</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25705" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25705" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_90p_dock_112324.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25705" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_90p_dock_112324.jpg" alt="The Progress 90 cargo craft carrying nearly three tons of food, fuel, and supplies approaches the International Space Station for a docking to the Poisk module. Credit: NASA+" width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_90p_dock_112324.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_90p_dock_112324.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_90p_dock_112324.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25705" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Progress 90 cargo craft carrying nearly three tons of food, fuel, and supplies approaches the International Space Station for a docking to the Poisk module. Credit: NASA+&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unpiloted Progress 90 spacecraft arrived at the space-facing port of the International Space Station’s Poisk module at 9:31 a.m. EST, Saturday, Nov. 23. The spacecraft launched at 7:22 a.m. (5:22 p.m. Baikonur time) Nov. 21, on a Soyuz rocket from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roscosmos spacecraft is delivering about three tons of food, fuel, and supplies for the Expedition 72 crew aboard the International Space Station and will remain docked for approximately six months before departing for a re-entry into Earth’s atmosphere to dispose of trash loaded by the crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt; on X, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here: &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_90p_dock_112324.jpg" alt="Space Delivery Arrives at Station Aboard Progress Cargo Craft"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Biology, Tech Studies Fill Day as Station Boosts Orbit</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/25/space-biology-tech-studies-fill-day-as-station-boosts-orbit/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25711" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25711" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qvmZpy"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25711" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e188529.jpg" alt="The International Space Station soars into an orbital sunset above the Pacific Ocean with the Soyuz MS-26 crew ship in the foreground and the Prichal docking module in the rear." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e188529.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e188529.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e188529.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25711" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The International Space Station soars into an orbital sunset above the Pacific Ocean with the Soyuz MS-26 crew ship in the foreground and the Prichal docking module in the rear.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew kicked off Thanksgiving week with a multitude of advanced biology and technology studies to improve human health and industry on and off the Earth. The orbital residents also focused on spacesuits and space cargo rounding out Monday aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping humans healthy on Earth and during space missions is a key research objective for NASA and its international partners. Scientists use the weightless environment of the orbital outpost to gain unique insights impossible to achieve on Earth’s surface supporting the medicine, commercial, and space industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; started their day wrapping up a biology experiment seeking ways to prevent space-caused stress effects and overcome age-related diseases on Earth. The duo processed samples in an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=333"&gt;artificial gravity-generating incubator&lt;/a&gt;, then stowed the research hardware, and disconnected a laptop computer closing out the investigation. During the experiment operations the astronauts used a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=8120"&gt;fluorescence microscope&lt;/a&gt; to observe the samples and understand how microgravity impacts inflammation and the immunity system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hague then moved on and set up the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7676"&gt;Life Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt; to begin exploring the feasibility of manufacturing &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9049"&gt;nanomaterials that mimic DNA&lt;/a&gt; and design advanced therapies enhancing quality of life. Wilmore collected station water samples for microbial analysis then swapped samples for a physics study exploring ways to separate viruses from biological fluids and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8855"&gt;improve disease detection methods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; started his day loading items inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft&lt;/a&gt; for return to Earth following its undocking on Thursday, Dec. 5. Next, he serviced the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1934"&gt;Additive Manufacturing Facility&lt;/a&gt;, a 3D printer, then collected &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9142"&gt;a variety of seed samples&lt;/a&gt; that will be returned to Earth for growing in school classrooms. At the end of his shift, Pettit turned on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8815"&gt;SphereCam-1&lt;/a&gt; to test its ability to capture ultra-high-resolution video for detailed imagery of spacecraft systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt;, station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; spent all day configuring spacesuit systems. She first serviced airlock oxygen and nitrogen tanks, then filtered and inspected suit cooling loops, and finally installed shields protecting suit life support systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos cosmonauts Ivan Vagner and Aleksandr Gorbunov worked together on Monday and continued unpacking the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-deilvery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Progress 90&lt;/a&gt; resupply ship that arrived on Saturday loaded with nearly three tons of food, fuel, and supplies. After the hatch to Progress 90 was first opened, crew members reported an unusual odor from the spacecraft. Flight controllers on the ground activated air scrubbing equipment as part of normal procedures, indicating that the odor likely was outgassing from materials inside the cargo spacecraft. The crew reported the odor dissipated quickly and cargo transfer operations are proceeding on schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vagner also cleaned ventilation systems and conducted photography inspections. Gorbunov downloaded radiation data then installed Earth observation hardware to image Earth’s nighttime atmosphere in near-ultraviolet wavelengths. Flight Engineer Alexey Ovchinin began his day exploring futuristic spacecraft and robotic piloting techniques, then transferred water from the newly arrived Progress 90, before finishing up in the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/07/29/new-module-successfully-docks-to-space-station/"&gt;Nauka science module&lt;/a&gt; cleaning fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Space Station is orbiting slightly higher today after the docked &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;Progress 89&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft fired its engines for three-and-a-half minutes early Monday. The debris avoidance maneuver positioned the orbital outpost farther away from a satellite fragment nearing the station’s flight path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e188529.jpg" alt="Space Biology, Tech Studies Fill Day as Station Boosts Orbit"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/25/space-biology-tech-studies-fill-day-as-station-boosts-orbit/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bio Tech Dominates Research Schedule to Advance Space, Earth Industries</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/26/bio-tech-dominates-research-schedule-to-advance-space-earth-industries/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25721" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25721" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qvmHrh"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25721" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e189824.jpg" alt="As the International Space Station soared 257 miles above, NASA astronaut Suni Williams captured this image of Florida at night. City lights illuminate the state and both the Gulf and Atlantic coasts are visible in this image." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e189824.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e189824.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e189824.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25721" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;As the International Space Station soared 257 miles above, NASA astronaut Suni Williams captured this image of Florida at night. City lights illuminate the state and both the Gulf and Atlantic coasts are visible in this image.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew studied micro-algae and DNA-like nanomaterials on Tuesday to improve health in space and on Earth. The orbital residents also worked on cargo transfers and lab maintenance aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; began his day processing radiation-resistant samples of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8907"&gt;Arthrospira C&lt;/a&gt; micro-algae and stowing them in an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=66"&gt;incubator&lt;/a&gt; for analysis. The samples will be exposed to different light intensities to observe how they affect the micro-algae’s cell growth and oxygen production. Results may advance the development of spacecraft life support systems and fresh food production in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, Hague joined Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; of NASA for a different research session mixing water with samples of messenger RNA, or mRNA, and protein to create &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9049"&gt;DNA-like nanomaterial products&lt;/a&gt; inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7676"&gt;Life Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt;. Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; then transferred the samples, exposed them to ultrasonic waves, and imaged them with a spectrophotometer to measure the intensity of light at different wavelengths and evaluate the quality of the nanomaterials. The samples will also be returned to Earth for further evaluation. Results may lead to improved therapies for Earth and space health conditions as well as advance the space economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilmore joined NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; and removed external research hardware from inside Kibo’s airlock. The hardware housed a variety of samples exposed to the vacuum of space such as polymers, photovoltaic devices, and more. The samples will be returned to Earth and examined to understand how space radiation, the extreme thermal environment, micrometeoroids, and more affect materials possibly benefitting the space industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, Pettit pedaled on an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=821"&gt;exercise cycle&lt;/a&gt; wearing breathing gear that measured his aerobic output in microgravity. He wrapped up his shift packing gear for return to Earth inside the SpaceX Dragon &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialresupply/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;cargo spacecraft&lt;/a&gt; due to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port on Thursday, Dec. 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner worked inside the Progress 89 resupply spacecraft on Tuesday that has been docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port since &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;Aug. 17&lt;/a&gt;. The duo first serviced the spacecraft’s docking mechanism then unpacked cargo for stowing inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/07/29/new-module-successfully-docks-to-space-station/"&gt;Nauka science module&lt;/a&gt;. Cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov had a light duty day primarily focusing on exercise inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;, jogging on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;treadmill&lt;/a&gt; and working out on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=973"&gt;advanced resistive exercise device&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_iss072e189824.jpg" alt="Bio Tech Dominates Research Schedule to Advance Space, Earth Industries"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/26/bio-tech-dominates-research-schedule-to-advance-space-earth-industries/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Tech Research Tops Crew Schedule Day Before Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/27/advanced-tech-research-tops-crew-schedule-day-before-thanksgiving/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25731" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25731" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DO2tTUmoXmk"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25731" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts (clockwise from bottom left) Nick Hague, Suni Williams, Butch Wilmore, and Don Pettit wish a Happy Thanksgiving in this video from the International Space Station. Credit: NASA/YouTube" width="840" height="473" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg?resize=768,433 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25731" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts (clockwise from bottom left) Nick Hague, Suni Williams, Butch Wilmore, and Don Pettit wish a Happy Thanksgiving in this &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; from the International Space Station. Credit: NASA/YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced technology research into DNA-like nanomaterials, bacterial genetic analysis, and 3D printing kept the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew busy the day before Thanksgiving. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also sent down a Thanksgiving message, checked out a Roscosmos cargo craft, and continued their standard orbital maintenance duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; kicked off her day with Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt;, both NASA astronauts, in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; mixing samples of messenger RNA, or mRNA, and protein with water to manufacture &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9049"&gt;nanomaterials that mimic DNA&lt;/a&gt;. Williams then imaged the samples using light intensity measurements to evaluate the quality of the nanomaterials. Results may benefit space manufacturing and lead to advanced therapies for Earthbound and space-caused health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; spent all day Wednesday collecting microbe samples throughout the station to analyze their genetic characteristics. Wilmore first swabbed areas the crew touches frequently then transferred those samples to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9026"&gt;genetic research hardware&lt;/a&gt; for analysis. The samples will be incubated for a few days before undergoing a DNA extraction process for identification. Doctors want to understand how antibiotic-resistant bacteria evolve in the microgravity environment in an effort reduce the risk of crew infection aboard spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; worked in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; configuring the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8707"&gt;Metal 3D Printer&lt;/a&gt; that may be able to manufacture spare parts during space missions reducing the need for resupply missions launched from Earth. Williams assisted Pettit removing a printed specimen from the 3D printer and replacing components inside the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four NASA astronauts sent down a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DO2tTUmoXmk"&gt;Thanksgiving message video&lt;/a&gt; highlighting their upcoming meal and expressing their gratitude for their families and living and working in space. The quartet along with the three Roscosmos cosmonauts aboard the space station will take the day off on Thursday enjoying a hearty meal, talking to family members on the ground, and relaxing aboard the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner worked throughout Wednesday checking ventilation systems and docking hardware inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;Progress 89&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port. The cosmonaut duo also took turns attaching electrodes to themselves recording their heart activity and measuring their blood pressure. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov updated laptop computer software and continued unpacking the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-deilvery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Progress 90&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg" alt="Advanced Tech Research Tops Crew Schedule Day Before Thanksgiving"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/27/advanced-tech-research-tops-crew-schedule-day-before-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Preps Space Botany Experiment, Packs Dragon for Return to Earth</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/29/crew-preps-space-botany-experiment-packs-dragon-for-return-to-earth/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25737" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25737" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qvt7qi"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25737" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg" alt="NASA astronaut and Expedition 72 Flight Engineer Nick Hague services samples of the Arthrospira C micro-algae for incubation and analysis." width="840" height="560" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg 8256w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=1024,683 1024w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25737" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronaut and Expedition 72 Flight Engineer Nick Hague services samples of the Arthrospira C micro-algae for incubation and analysis.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew is back to work following a day off yesterday to observe the Thanksgiving holiday. Space botany experiment prep and cargo operations topped Friday’s schedule aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; as three NASA astronauts prepped the SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft for return and another installed science gear that will assess how plants respond to different levels of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; spent some of the day packing gear for return to Earth inside the SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft, which is set to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt; module’s forward port on Thursday, Dec. 5. Dragon arrived to the orbiting lab on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialresupply/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;Nov. 5&lt;/a&gt;, delivering over 6,000 pounds of science and cargo to the crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pettit also penciled in some time to answer questions about life in orbit during an amateur radio call with students in Caltanissetta, Italy. Meanwhile, after Wednesday’s processing of radiant-resistant &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8907"&gt;Arthrospira C&lt;/a&gt; micro-algae samples, Hague removed the four sample containers and swapped in a new set to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=66"&gt;BioLab Incubator&lt;/a&gt;. The samples will be exposed to different light intensities to observe how they affect the micro-algae’s cell growth, which could advance spacecraft life support system development and fresh food production on future space missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Harmony module, station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; started her day by gathering hardware for future &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; operations. She then collected water samples from the device’s distribution reservoir before installing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;Plant Habitat-07&lt;/a&gt; science carrier. The science carrier will host “Outredgeous” romaine lettuce plants as they grow in microgravity for crew members to assess how different amounts of water affect the growth of the plants. Results could identify how different moisture environments alter the production and nutritional content of lettuce grown in space and could improve how food crops are grown on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the day, Williams assisted Hague with an ultrasound exam as she scanned veins in his neck, shoulders, and behind the knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/07/29/new-module-successfully-docks-to-space-station/"&gt;Nauka&lt;/a&gt; module, Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner rerouted cables throughout the day. Vagner then moved into the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya&lt;/a&gt; module to assess lighting conditions and later continued to unpack the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Progress 90&lt;/a&gt; cargo spacecraft, which docked to the station’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk&lt;/a&gt; module on Nov. 23. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov completed some computer work before ending his day by practicing his piloting techniques during a Pilot-T session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt; on X, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly updates from NASA Johnson Space Center at: &lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here: &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg" alt="Crew Preps Space Botany Experiment, Packs Dragon for Return to Earth"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/29/crew-preps-space-botany-experiment-packs-dragon-for-return-to-earth/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Packs Dragon for Departure This Week</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/02/crew-packs-dragon-for-departure-this-week/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25744" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25744" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qxDLWg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25744" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Don Pettit pose for a portrait in front of the Advanced Plant Habitat designed to support commercial and fundamental plant research in microgravity." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25744" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Don Pettit pose for a portrait in front of the Advanced Plant Habitat designed to support commercial and fundamental plant research in microgravity.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew is packing a SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft ahead of its departure later this week. The seven astronauts and cosmonauts also kept up a variety of space biology and lab maintenance tasks aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo packing is at the top of the schedule this week as the SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft nears its undocking targeted for 11:05 a.m. EST on Thursday, Dec. 5. NASA’s live coverage of undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; joined forces on Monday morning loading Dragon with return cargo as it prepares to depart the Harmony module’s forward port after being docked for one month. Pettit then worked with Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; during the afternoon strapping down the hardware inside Dragon. The trio plus Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; will work during the week stowing critical research samples and finalized experiments inside the spacecraft for analysis in labs on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four NASA astronauts also continued their regularly scheduled research objectives studying space biology and servicing a host of science equipment. Williams with assistance from Wilmore activated mixing tubes supporting &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22nanoracks+module-9%22&amp;amp;i=72&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;student-designed experiments&lt;/a&gt; that observe how microgravity affects proteins and bacteria potentially benefitting human health on and off the Earth. Williams also processed bacteria and yeast samples for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9029"&gt;biomanufacturing study&lt;/a&gt; possibly enabling the production of food and medicine in space. Pettit spun his blood sample in a centrifuge then stowed it in a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=56"&gt;science freezer&lt;/a&gt; for later analysis. Hague installed the Multi-Purpose Experiment Platform, a device that can deploy scientific payloads in the vacuum of space, into the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s airlock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the Roscosmos segment of the orbital outpost, cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov unloaded cargo from the Progress 90 resupply ship that docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-deilvery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Nov. 23&lt;/a&gt;. He also set up imaging hardware to view natural and human-caused conditions on Earth using different wavelengths. Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner partnered together throughout Monday servicing communications, computer, and electronics hardware in Zvezda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg" alt="Crew Packs Dragon for Departure This Week"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/02/crew-packs-dragon-for-departure-this-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Finalizing Science For Return to Earth Aboard Dragon</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/03/crew-finalizing-science-for-return-to-earth-aboard-dragon/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25750" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25750" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qvfWEA"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25750 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg" alt="Expedition 72 crewmates Suni Williams of NASA and Aleksandr Gorbunov of Roscosmos wear personal protective equipment shortly after the hatches opened to the newly arrived SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft on Nov. 5, 2024. Photo credit: NASA" width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25750" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Expedition 72 crewmates Suni Williams of NASA and Aleksandr Gorbunov of Roscosmos wear personal protective equipment shortly after the hatches opened to the newly arrived SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft on Nov. 5, 2024.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew is packing up finalized science experiments this week for return to Earth aboard the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also studied antibiotic resistant bacteria and set up space botany hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt;, both from NASA, kicked off their day transferring research samples from station science freezers into portable &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1092"&gt;POLAR freezers&lt;/a&gt; that will soon be installed inside the departing Dragon. Williams then joined NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; loading and strapping down more cargo inside Dragon for retrieval and analysis on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragon is scheduled to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-to-cover-its-31st-spacex-resupply-mission-station-departure/"&gt;11:05 a.m. EST on Thursday&lt;/a&gt; for a splashdown off the coast of Florida the following day. NASA’s live coverage of undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pettit later spent the rest of his shift with NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; processing bacteria samples in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt; modules to understand why some pathogens are more potent in the microgravity environment. The duo was using genetic analysis techniques to identify the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9026"&gt;antibiotic resistant organisms&lt;/a&gt; and help researchers protect crew health on long-term space missions. Those samples will also be collected and packed inside Dragon this week for return and analysis back on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams set up research components inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; to support an upcoming experiment to understand how different water levels affect plant growth in space and the microbes that live on plants. Results may lead to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;improved methods for growing food&lt;/a&gt; on Earth and in space. Hague began installing a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=883"&gt;small satellite deployer&lt;/a&gt; on Kibo’s multipurpose experiment platform that will soon be placed into the vacuum of space to release a series of CubeSats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the Roscosmos segment of the space station, Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov used different wavelengths to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22uragan%22&amp;amp;i=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;image natural and human-caused conditions on Earth&lt;/a&gt; then jogged on a treadmill for a fitness evaluation. His fellow cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner spent their day monitoring carbon dioxide levels and servicing the atmospheric purification system in the orbital lab’s Roscosmos segment among other life support tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt; on X, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here: &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg" alt="Crew Finalizing Science For Return to Earth Aboard Dragon"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/03/crew-finalizing-science-for-return-to-earth-aboard-dragon/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Packed With Science and Now Targets Friday Undocking</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/04/dragon-packed-with-science-and-now-targets-friday-undocking/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25758" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25758" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qtUw9n"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25758 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg" alt="The SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft, carrying over 6,000 pounds of science, supplies, and hardware, approaches the station on Nov. 5 above the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Uruguay." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25758" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft, carrying over 6,000 pounds of science, supplies, and hardware, approaches the station on Nov. 5 above the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Uruguay.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing research samples and station hardware for return to Earth were the top tasks aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday. The seven-member &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew also serviced a variety of science hardware and electronics gear throughout the orbital lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts are finishing up the loading of completed science experiments and lab hardware inside the Dragon spacecraft for retrieval and analysis on Earth. NASA and SpaceX now are targeting Friday, Dec. 6, for the return of the resupply spacecraft. Mission managers waved off the planned return on Thursday, Dec. 5, due to forecasted high winds at the splashdown site off the coast of Florida. NASA’s live coverage of Dragon’s undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://NASA+"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt; as the spacecraft autonomously undocks from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port around 11:05 a.m. on Friday. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and station commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; kicked off her day installing the sample-packed &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=8508"&gt;Space Automated Lab Incubator&lt;/a&gt; inside Dragon. NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; continued her work loading and securing &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1092"&gt;portable science freezers&lt;/a&gt; filled with research samples and powered lockers containing finalized experiments inside the Earthbound spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and Hague also had time to join each other in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; replacing components and resizing a spacesuit ahead of a series spacewalks planned for early next year. Wilmore spent all day Wednesday loading cargo from the station into Dragon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; started his day in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; configuring a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=883"&gt;small satellite orbital deployer&lt;/a&gt; that will soon be placed into the vacuum of space to release a series of CubeSats. Pettit, a four-time space station visitor, wrapped up his shift replacing experiment samples inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=317"&gt;Combustion Integrated Rack&lt;/a&gt; readying the research device for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8268"&gt;spacecraft fire safety investigation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov also worked on cargo duties but on the other side of the orbital outpost. Gorbunov unpacked some of the nearly three tons of cargo launched aboard the Progress 90 cargo craft on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/21/progress-cargo-spacecraft-launches-headed-for-a-saturday-docking/"&gt;Nov. 21&lt;/a&gt; and docking to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Nov. 23&lt;/a&gt;. The first-time space flyer completed his day inspecting and photographing air conditioning hardware in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner partnered together throughout the day Wednesday servicing a host of communications and electronics hardware in the orbital outpost’s Roscosmos segment. Ovchinin then moved on and checked ventilation equipment inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt;. Vagner conducted a photo-inspection of windows inside Zvezda then collected his hair samples for biological analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg" alt="Dragon Packed With Science and Now Targets Friday Undocking"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/04/dragon-packed-with-science-and-now-targets-friday-undocking/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Departure Adjusted to Next Week, Crew Works Science and Spacewalk Preps</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/05/dragon-departure-adjusted-to-next-week-crew-works-science-and-spacewalk-preps/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25770" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25770" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qxDo8c"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25770" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg" alt="Astronauts Suni Williams and Tracy C. Dyson look out the cupola, the International Space Station's &amp;quot;window to the world,&amp;quot; while orbiting above the Atlantic Ocean on Sept. 1, 2024." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25770" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronauts Suni Williams and Tracy C. Dyson look out the cupola, the International Space Station’s “window to the world,” while orbiting above the Atlantic Ocean on Sept. 1, 2024.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The science-packed SpaceX Dragon spacecraft will wait another week before departing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; as mission managers monitor weather conditions at the splashdown sites. Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew geared up for a spacewalk planned later in December and serviced an array of science hardware and exercise equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission managers waved off the planned return of the Dragon resupply spacecraft on Friday, Dec. 6, due to forecasted unfavorable weather conditions at the splashdown site off the coast of Florida. NASA and SpaceX now are targeting Thursday, Dec. 12, for the next return opportunity due to an extended period of high sun exposure at the space station over the next week. NASA’s live coverage of Dragon’s undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt; as the spacecraft autonomously undocks from the Harmony module’s forward port around 11:05 a.m. on Thursday. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts completed installing &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1092"&gt;science freezers&lt;/a&gt; packed with research samples and powered lockers with completed experiments inside Dragon. The crewmates also loaded a host of station hardware inside the spacecraft and secured it for the return to Earth. NASA and SpaceX support personnel will retrieve Dragon after its return to Earth and send the preserved scientific specimens and orbital gear to labs for analysis and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, research continued on the space station as NASA astronauts and flight engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; split their day working on a pair of space physics experiments. Wilmore first opened up the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=341"&gt;Microgravity Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt; and removed research components for a study that explored ways to separate viruses from biological fluids and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8855"&gt;improve disease detection methods&lt;/a&gt;. Pettit followed and then installed new hardware in the glovebox that will support an investigation that may enable bulk crystal growth and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8968"&gt;large-scale semiconductor manufacturing in space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and station commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; spent a second day in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; for more spacesuit work ahead of a series of spacewalk planned for early next year. Williams, a three-time space station resident, first swapped a data recorder box from one suit to another. Afterward, she inspected and serviced the spacesuit’s life support gear following the previous day’s suit resizing and configuration work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and flight engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; began his shift in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt; performing a six-month inspection on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;COLBERT treadmill&lt;/a&gt;’s hardware and components. Hague then wrapped up his day inspecting tethers and gathering tools for a pair of cosmonauts who preparing for a spacewalk planned before Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos cosmonauts and flight engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner spent most of Thursday studying for the year’s last spacewalk planned for Thursday, Dec. 19. The duo collected tools from Hague and reviewed procedures that would see the spacewalkers spend about six-and-a-half hours in space removing external science experiments and relocating European robotic arm hardware on the station’s Roscosmos segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov completed an Earth observation session imaging in different wavelengths the effects of natural and human-caused impacts on the landscape below. The first-time space flyer moved on and inspected power supply units in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt; and filled an oxygen generator in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg" alt="Dragon Departure Adjusted to Next Week, Crew Works Science and Spacewalk Preps"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/05/dragon-departure-adjusted-to-next-week-crew-works-science-and-spacewalk-preps/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robots, Microbes, and Plants Pack Research Schedule at End of Week</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/06/robots-microbes-and-plants-pack-research-schedule-at-end-of-week/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25776" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25776" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qy1iqt"&gt;&lt;img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25776" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg" alt="Expedition 72 Commander Suni Williams of NASA smiles for a portrait inside the International Space Station's Zvezda service module during dinner time." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25776" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Expedition 72 Commander Suni Williams of NASA smiles for a portrait inside the International Space Station’s Zvezda service module during dinner time.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotic tentacles, antibiotic resistant microbes, and space agriculture topped the research schedule aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; at the end of the week. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew members are also preparing for a spacewalk and continuing maintenance on the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; had a busy day on Friday researching how robots could capture orbital debris and growing safe and nutritious food in space. Williams activated an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1891"&gt;Astrobee robotic free-flyer&lt;/a&gt; outfitted with &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9127"&gt;tentacle-like arms&lt;/a&gt; containing gecko-like adhesive pads. Then, she and ground controllers monitored the Astrobee as it demonstrated docking maneuvers that could be used to remove orbital debris and capture satellites for servicing. She also trimmed red romaine lettuce leaves being grown in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; to test different moisture levels that may support &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;growing crops in space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; worked in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; sequencing microbial DNA to identify the characteristics of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9026"&gt;antibiotic resistant organisms&lt;/a&gt; in microgravity. Results may reveal why some pathogens are more potent in space and address the risks to astronaut health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; started his day processing bacteria and yeast samples to learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9029"&gt;produce food and medicine in space&lt;/a&gt;. Afterward, Hague, with assistance from NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;wrapped up a six-month inspection and cleaning of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;COLBERT treadmill&lt;/a&gt;’s hardware and components inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;. Wilmore would spend the rest of Friday off-duty after a busy week of microbial research and cargo packing inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner continued preparing for a Dec. 19 spacewalk to remove external science experiments and relocate European robotic arm hardware.&amp;nbsp;The duo first checked the hatch for leaks inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt; where they will exit the station to begin a planned six-hour and 40-minute spacewalk. Afterward, the pair from Roscosmos collected and organized the spacewalking tools they will use for the first excursion of Expedition 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov began his day measuring his body mass using a version of Newton’s first law of motion, force equals mass times acceleration. Next, he started his shift on orbital plumbing duties before ending his day inspecting a gas-liquid heat exchanger in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg" alt="Robots, Microbes, and Plants Pack Research Schedule at End of Week"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/06/robots-microbes-and-plants-pack-research-schedule-at-end-of-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
