<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NASA Space Station Blog</title>
    <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/</link>
    <description>The official blog of NASA's space station news.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 05:00:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Tech Research Tops Crew Schedule Day Before Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/27/advanced-tech-research-tops-crew-schedule-day-before-thanksgiving/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25731" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25731" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DO2tTUmoXmk"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25731" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts (clockwise from bottom left) Nick Hague, Suni Williams, Butch Wilmore, and Don Pettit wish a Happy Thanksgiving in this video from the International Space Station. Credit: NASA/YouTube" width="840" height="473" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg?resize=768,433 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25731" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts (clockwise from bottom left) Nick Hague, Suni Williams, Butch Wilmore, and Don Pettit wish a Happy Thanksgiving in this &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; from the International Space Station. Credit: NASA/YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced technology research into DNA-like nanomaterials, bacterial genetic analysis, and 3D printing kept the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew busy the day before Thanksgiving. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also sent down a Thanksgiving message, checked out a Roscosmos cargo craft, and continued their standard orbital maintenance duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; kicked off her day with Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt;, both NASA astronauts, in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; mixing samples of messenger RNA, or mRNA, and protein with water to manufacture &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9049"&gt;nanomaterials that mimic DNA&lt;/a&gt;. Williams then imaged the samples using light intensity measurements to evaluate the quality of the nanomaterials. Results may benefit space manufacturing and lead to advanced therapies for Earthbound and space-caused health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; spent all day Wednesday collecting microbe samples throughout the station to analyze their genetic characteristics. Wilmore first swabbed areas the crew touches frequently then transferred those samples to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9026"&gt;genetic research hardware&lt;/a&gt; for analysis. The samples will be incubated for a few days before undergoing a DNA extraction process for identification. Doctors want to understand how antibiotic-resistant bacteria evolve in the microgravity environment in an effort reduce the risk of crew infection aboard spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; worked in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; configuring the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8707"&gt;Metal 3D Printer&lt;/a&gt; that may be able to manufacture spare parts during space missions reducing the need for resupply missions launched from Earth. Williams assisted Pettit removing a printed specimen from the 3D printer and replacing components inside the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four NASA astronauts sent down a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DO2tTUmoXmk"&gt;Thanksgiving message video&lt;/a&gt; highlighting their upcoming meal and expressing their gratitude for their families and living and working in space. The quartet along with the three Roscosmos cosmonauts aboard the space station will take the day off on Thursday enjoying a hearty meal, talking to family members on the ground, and relaxing aboard the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner worked throughout Wednesday checking ventilation systems and docking hardware inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/08/17/space-delivery-arrives-after-roscosmos-cargo-craft-docks/"&gt;Progress 89&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port. The cosmonaut duo also took turns attaching electrodes to themselves recording their heart activity and measuring their blood pressure. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov updated laptop computer software and continued unpacking the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-deilvery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Progress 90&lt;/a&gt; cargo craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_exp72_thanksgiving_message_112724.jpg" alt="Advanced Tech Research Tops Crew Schedule Day Before Thanksgiving"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/27/advanced-tech-research-tops-crew-schedule-day-before-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Preps Space Botany Experiment, Packs Dragon for Return to Earth</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/29/crew-preps-space-botany-experiment-packs-dragon-for-return-to-earth/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25737" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25737" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qvt7qi"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25737" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg" alt="NASA astronaut and Expedition 72 Flight Engineer Nick Hague services samples of the Arthrospira C micro-algae for incubation and analysis." width="840" height="560" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg 8256w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=1024,683 1024w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25737" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronaut and Expedition 72 Flight Engineer Nick Hague services samples of the Arthrospira C micro-algae for incubation and analysis.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew is back to work following a day off yesterday to observe the Thanksgiving holiday. Space botany experiment prep and cargo operations topped Friday’s schedule aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; as three NASA astronauts prepped the SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft for return and another installed science gear that will assess how plants respond to different levels of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; spent some of the day packing gear for return to Earth inside the SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft, which is set to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt; module’s forward port on Thursday, Dec. 5. Dragon arrived to the orbiting lab on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialresupply/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;Nov. 5&lt;/a&gt;, delivering over 6,000 pounds of science and cargo to the crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pettit also penciled in some time to answer questions about life in orbit during an amateur radio call with students in Caltanissetta, Italy. Meanwhile, after Wednesday’s processing of radiant-resistant &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8907"&gt;Arthrospira C&lt;/a&gt; micro-algae samples, Hague removed the four sample containers and swapped in a new set to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=66"&gt;BioLab Incubator&lt;/a&gt;. The samples will be exposed to different light intensities to observe how they affect the micro-algae’s cell growth, which could advance spacecraft life support system development and fresh food production on future space missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Harmony module, station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; started her day by gathering hardware for future &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; operations. She then collected water samples from the device’s distribution reservoir before installing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;Plant Habitat-07&lt;/a&gt; science carrier. The science carrier will host “Outredgeous” romaine lettuce plants as they grow in microgravity for crew members to assess how different amounts of water affect the growth of the plants. Results could identify how different moisture environments alter the production and nutritional content of lettuce grown in space and could improve how food crops are grown on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the day, Williams assisted Hague with an ultrasound exam as she scanned veins in his neck, shoulders, and behind the knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/07/29/new-module-successfully-docks-to-space-station/"&gt;Nauka&lt;/a&gt; module, Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner rerouted cables throughout the day. Vagner then moved into the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya&lt;/a&gt; module to assess lighting conditions and later continued to unpack the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Progress 90&lt;/a&gt; cargo spacecraft, which docked to the station’s &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk&lt;/a&gt; module on Nov. 23. Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov completed some computer work before ending his day by practicing his piloting techniques during a Pilot-T session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt; on X, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get weekly updates from NASA Johnson Space Center at: &lt;a href="https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/"&gt;https://roundupreads.jsc.nasa.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here: &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/54154722977_b8a8b1e6cb_o.jpg" alt="Crew Preps Space Botany Experiment, Packs Dragon for Return to Earth"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/29/crew-preps-space-botany-experiment-packs-dragon-for-return-to-earth/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Packs Dragon for Departure This Week</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/02/crew-packs-dragon-for-departure-this-week/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25744" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25744" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qxDLWg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25744" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Don Pettit pose for a portrait in front of the Advanced Plant Habitat designed to support commercial and fundamental plant research in microgravity." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25744" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;NASA astronauts Suni Williams and Don Pettit pose for a portrait in front of the Advanced Plant Habitat designed to support commercial and fundamental plant research in microgravity.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew is packing a SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft ahead of its departure later this week. The seven astronauts and cosmonauts also kept up a variety of space biology and lab maintenance tasks aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo packing is at the top of the schedule this week as the SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft nears its undocking targeted for 11:05 a.m. EST on Thursday, Dec. 5. NASA’s live coverage of undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; joined forces on Monday morning loading Dragon with return cargo as it prepares to depart the Harmony module’s forward port after being docked for one month. Pettit then worked with Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; during the afternoon strapping down the hardware inside Dragon. The trio plus Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; will work during the week stowing critical research samples and finalized experiments inside the spacecraft for analysis in labs on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four NASA astronauts also continued their regularly scheduled research objectives studying space biology and servicing a host of science equipment. Williams with assistance from Wilmore activated mixing tubes supporting &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22nanoracks+module-9%22&amp;amp;i=72&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;student-designed experiments&lt;/a&gt; that observe how microgravity affects proteins and bacteria potentially benefitting human health on and off the Earth. Williams also processed bacteria and yeast samples for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9029"&gt;biomanufacturing study&lt;/a&gt; possibly enabling the production of food and medicine in space. Pettit spun his blood sample in a centrifuge then stowed it in a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=56"&gt;science freezer&lt;/a&gt; for later analysis. Hague installed the Multi-Purpose Experiment Platform, a device that can deploy scientific payloads in the vacuum of space, into the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;’s airlock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the Roscosmos segment of the orbital outpost, cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov unloaded cargo from the Progress 90 resupply ship that docked to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;’s rear port on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-deilvery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Nov. 23&lt;/a&gt;. He also set up imaging hardware to view natural and human-caused conditions on Earth using different wavelengths. Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner partnered together throughout Monday servicing communications, computer, and electronics hardware in Zvezda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e281303.jpg" alt="Crew Packs Dragon for Departure This Week"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/02/crew-packs-dragon-for-departure-this-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Finalizing Science For Return to Earth Aboard Dragon</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/03/crew-finalizing-science-for-return-to-earth-aboard-dragon/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25750" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25750" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qvfWEA"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25750 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg" alt="Expedition 72 crewmates Suni Williams of NASA and Aleksandr Gorbunov of Roscosmos wear personal protective equipment shortly after the hatches opened to the newly arrived SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft on Nov. 5, 2024. Photo credit: NASA" width="900" height="506" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25750" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Expedition 72 crewmates Suni Williams of NASA and Aleksandr Gorbunov of Roscosmos wear personal protective equipment shortly after the hatches opened to the newly arrived SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft on Nov. 5, 2024.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew is packing up finalized science experiments this week for return to Earth aboard the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also studied antibiotic resistant bacteria and set up space botany hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt;, both from NASA, kicked off their day transferring research samples from station science freezers into portable &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1092"&gt;POLAR freezers&lt;/a&gt; that will soon be installed inside the departing Dragon. Williams then joined NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; loading and strapping down more cargo inside Dragon for retrieval and analysis on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragon is scheduled to undock from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port at &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-to-cover-its-31st-spacex-resupply-mission-station-departure/"&gt;11:05 a.m. EST on Thursday&lt;/a&gt; for a splashdown off the coast of Florida the following day. NASA’s live coverage of undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pettit later spent the rest of his shift with NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; processing bacteria samples in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt; modules to understand why some pathogens are more potent in the microgravity environment. The duo was using genetic analysis techniques to identify the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9026"&gt;antibiotic resistant organisms&lt;/a&gt; and help researchers protect crew health on long-term space missions. Those samples will also be collected and packed inside Dragon this week for return and analysis back on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams set up research components inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; to support an upcoming experiment to understand how different water levels affect plant growth in space and the microbes that live on plants. Results may lead to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;improved methods for growing food&lt;/a&gt; on Earth and in space. Hague began installing a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=883"&gt;small satellite deployer&lt;/a&gt; on Kibo’s multipurpose experiment platform that will soon be placed into the vacuum of space to release a series of CubeSats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the Roscosmos segment of the space station, Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov used different wavelengths to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22uragan%22&amp;amp;i=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;image natural and human-caused conditions on Earth&lt;/a&gt; then jogged on a treadmill for a fitness evaluation. His fellow cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner spent their day monitoring carbon dioxide levels and servicing the atmospheric purification system in the orbital lab’s Roscosmos segment among other life support tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt; on X, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here: &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e145408.jpg" alt="Crew Finalizing Science For Return to Earth Aboard Dragon"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/03/crew-finalizing-science-for-return-to-earth-aboard-dragon/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Packed With Science and Now Targets Friday Undocking</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/04/dragon-packed-with-science-and-now-targets-friday-undocking/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25758" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25758" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qtUw9n"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25758 size-full" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg" alt="The SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft, carrying over 6,000 pounds of science, supplies, and hardware, approaches the station on Nov. 5 above the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Uruguay." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25758" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft, carrying over 6,000 pounds of science, supplies, and hardware, approaches the station on Nov. 5 above the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Uruguay.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing research samples and station hardware for return to Earth were the top tasks aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday. The seven-member &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew also serviced a variety of science hardware and electronics gear throughout the orbital lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts are finishing up the loading of completed science experiments and lab hardware inside the Dragon spacecraft for retrieval and analysis on Earth. NASA and SpaceX now are targeting Friday, Dec. 6, for the return of the resupply spacecraft. Mission managers waved off the planned return on Thursday, Dec. 5, due to forecasted high winds at the splashdown site off the coast of Florida. NASA’s live coverage of Dragon’s undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://NASA+"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt; as the spacecraft autonomously undocks from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s forward port around 11:05 a.m. on Friday. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and station commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; kicked off her day installing the sample-packed &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=8508"&gt;Space Automated Lab Incubator&lt;/a&gt; inside Dragon. NASA astronauts &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; continued her work loading and securing &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1092"&gt;portable science freezers&lt;/a&gt; filled with research samples and powered lockers containing finalized experiments inside the Earthbound spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and Hague also had time to join each other in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; replacing components and resizing a spacesuit ahead of a series spacewalks planned for early next year. Wilmore spent all day Wednesday loading cargo from the station into Dragon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; started his day in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; configuring a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=883"&gt;small satellite orbital deployer&lt;/a&gt; that will soon be placed into the vacuum of space to release a series of CubeSats. Pettit, a four-time space station visitor, wrapped up his shift replacing experiment samples inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=317"&gt;Combustion Integrated Rack&lt;/a&gt; readying the research device for a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8268"&gt;spacecraft fire safety investigation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov also worked on cargo duties but on the other side of the orbital outpost. Gorbunov unpacked some of the nearly three tons of cargo launched aboard the Progress 90 cargo craft on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/21/progress-cargo-spacecraft-launches-headed-for-a-saturday-docking/"&gt;Nov. 21&lt;/a&gt; and docking to the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/"&gt;Nov. 23&lt;/a&gt;. The first-time space flyer completed his day inspecting and photographing air conditioning hardware in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner partnered together throughout the day Wednesday servicing a host of communications and electronics hardware in the orbital outpost’s Roscosmos segment. Ovchinin then moved on and checked ventilation equipment inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt;. Vagner conducted a photo-inspection of windows inside Zvezda then collected his hair samples for biological analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e147436.jpg" alt="Dragon Packed With Science and Now Targets Friday Undocking"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/04/dragon-packed-with-science-and-now-targets-friday-undocking/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Departure Adjusted to Next Week, Crew Works Science and Spacewalk Preps</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/05/dragon-departure-adjusted-to-next-week-crew-works-science-and-spacewalk-preps/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25770" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25770" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qxDo8c"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25770" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg" alt="Astronauts Suni Williams and Tracy C. Dyson look out the cupola, the International Space Station's &amp;quot;window to the world,&amp;quot; while orbiting above the Atlantic Ocean on Sept. 1, 2024." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25770" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronauts Suni Williams and Tracy C. Dyson look out the cupola, the International Space Station’s “window to the world,” while orbiting above the Atlantic Ocean on Sept. 1, 2024.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The science-packed SpaceX Dragon spacecraft will wait another week before departing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; as mission managers monitor weather conditions at the splashdown sites. Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew geared up for a spacewalk planned later in December and serviced an array of science hardware and exercise equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission managers waved off the planned return of the Dragon resupply spacecraft on Friday, Dec. 6, due to forecasted unfavorable weather conditions at the splashdown site off the coast of Florida. NASA and SpaceX now are targeting Thursday, Dec. 12, for the next return opportunity due to an extended period of high sun exposure at the space station over the next week. NASA’s live coverage of Dragon’s undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on &lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt; as the spacecraft autonomously undocks from the Harmony module’s forward port around 11:05 a.m. on Thursday. Learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt; through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronauts completed installing &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1092"&gt;science freezers&lt;/a&gt; packed with research samples and powered lockers with completed experiments inside Dragon. The crewmates also loaded a host of station hardware inside the spacecraft and secured it for the return to Earth. NASA and SpaceX support personnel will retrieve Dragon after its return to Earth and send the preserved scientific specimens and orbital gear to labs for analysis and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, research continued on the space station as NASA astronauts and flight engineers &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; split their day working on a pair of space physics experiments. Wilmore first opened up the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=341"&gt;Microgravity Science Glovebox&lt;/a&gt; and removed research components for a study that explored ways to separate viruses from biological fluids and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8855"&gt;improve disease detection methods&lt;/a&gt;. Pettit followed and then installed new hardware in the glovebox that will support an investigation that may enable bulk crystal growth and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8968"&gt;large-scale semiconductor manufacturing in space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and station commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; spent a second day in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; for more spacesuit work ahead of a series of spacewalk planned for early next year. Williams, a three-time space station resident, first swapped a data recorder box from one suit to another. Afterward, she inspected and serviced the spacesuit’s life support gear following the previous day’s suit resizing and configuration work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and flight engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; began his shift in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt; performing a six-month inspection on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;COLBERT treadmill&lt;/a&gt;’s hardware and components. Hague then wrapped up his day inspecting tethers and gathering tools for a pair of cosmonauts who preparing for a spacewalk planned before Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos cosmonauts and flight engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner spent most of Thursday studying for the year’s last spacewalk planned for Thursday, Dec. 19. The duo collected tools from Hague and reviewed procedures that would see the spacewalkers spend about six-and-a-half hours in space removing external science experiments and relocating European robotic arm hardware on the station’s Roscosmos segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov completed an Earth observation session imaging in different wavelengths the effects of natural and human-caused impacts on the landscape below. The first-time space flyer moved on and inspected power supply units in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt; and filled an oxygen generator in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss071e581520.jpg" alt="Dragon Departure Adjusted to Next Week, Crew Works Science and Spacewalk Preps"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/05/dragon-departure-adjusted-to-next-week-crew-works-science-and-spacewalk-preps/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robots, Microbes, and Plants Pack Research Schedule at End of Week</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/06/robots-microbes-and-plants-pack-research-schedule-at-end-of-week/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25776" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25776" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qy1iqt"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25776" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg" alt="Expedition 72 Commander Suni Williams of NASA smiles for a portrait inside the International Space Station's Zvezda service module during dinner time." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25776" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Expedition 72 Commander Suni Williams of NASA smiles for a portrait inside the International Space Station’s Zvezda service module during dinner time.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotic tentacles, antibiotic resistant microbes, and space agriculture topped the research schedule aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; at the end of the week. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew members are also preparing for a spacewalk and continuing maintenance on the orbital outpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA astronaut and station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; had a busy day on Friday researching how robots could capture orbital debris and growing safe and nutritious food in space. Williams activated an &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1891"&gt;Astrobee robotic free-flyer&lt;/a&gt; outfitted with &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9127"&gt;tentacle-like arms&lt;/a&gt; containing gecko-like adhesive pads. Then, she and ground controllers monitored the Astrobee as it demonstrated docking maneuvers that could be used to remove orbital debris and capture satellites for servicing. She also trimmed red romaine lettuce leaves being grown in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=2036"&gt;Advanced Plant Habitat&lt;/a&gt; to test different moisture levels that may support &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9195"&gt;growing crops in space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; worked in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; sequencing microbial DNA to identify the characteristics of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9026"&gt;antibiotic resistant organisms&lt;/a&gt; in microgravity. Results may reveal why some pathogens are more potent in space and address the risks to astronaut health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; started his day processing bacteria and yeast samples to learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9029"&gt;produce food and medicine in space&lt;/a&gt;. Afterward, Hague, with assistance from NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;wrapped up a six-month inspection and cleaning of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;COLBERT treadmill&lt;/a&gt;’s hardware and components inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/tranquility-module/"&gt;Tranquility module&lt;/a&gt;. Wilmore would spend the rest of Friday off-duty after a busy week of microbial research and cargo packing inside the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/05/spacex-dragon-cargo-spacecraft-docks-to-harmony-module/"&gt;SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner continued preparing for a Dec. 19 spacewalk to remove external science experiments and relocate European robotic arm hardware.&amp;nbsp;The duo first checked the hatch for leaks inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt; where they will exit the station to begin a planned six-hour and 40-minute spacewalk. Afterward, the pair from Roscosmos collected and organized the spacewalking tools they will use for the first excursion of Expedition 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov began his day measuring his body mass using a version of Newton’s first law of motion, force equals mass times acceleration. Next, he started his shift on orbital plumbing duties before ending his day inspecting a gas-liquid heat exchanger in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zvezda-service-module/"&gt;Zvezda service module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e189112.jpg" alt="Robots, Microbes, and Plants Pack Research Schedule at End of Week"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/06/robots-microbes-and-plants-pack-research-schedule-at-end-of-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Begins with Spacewalk Preps, Physics, and Biology Research</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/09/week-begins-with-spacewalk-preps-physics-and-biology-research/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25780" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25780" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qyVVZD"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25780" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e316172.jpg" alt="The International Space Station is pictured from the SpaceX Dragon crew spacecraft by a SpaceX Crew-8 member shortly after undocking on Oct. 23, 2024." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e316172.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e316172.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e316172.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25780" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The International Space Station is pictured from the SpaceX Dragon crew spacecraft by a SpaceX Crew-8 member shortly after undocking on Oct. 23, 2024.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacesuits topped the schedule for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew on Monday as a pair of cosmonauts get ready for a spacewalk planned for next week. The &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; residents also kicked off the workweek focusing their research activities on physics and biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner of Roscosmos are gearing up for a spacewalk expected to begin at approximately 10:10 a.m. EST on Dec. 19. The duo will open the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt;’s hatch and spend about six hours and 40 minutes removing external science experiments and relocating European robotic arm hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ovchinin and Vagner took turns at the beginning of their shift on Monday assessing their hand grip strength due to the dexterity required to complete their spacewalk tasks inside the pressurized Orlan spacesuits. Afterward, the cosmonauts installed a variety of life support components and other gear on their individual Orlan suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current space station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; and Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt;, both from NASA, also worked on spacesuit maintenance but on the other side of the space station inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt;. The duo scrubbed suit and airlock cooling loops, inspected life support gear, and checked out radio communications hardware ahead of more spacewalks planned for early next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Williams and Pettit had more tasks planned Monday including a vision test using a standard eye chart with NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt;. Williams also inserted &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9106"&gt;samples of colloids&lt;/a&gt;, or particles mixed inside a substance to create a gel, inside a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=8120"&gt;fluorescence microscope&lt;/a&gt; for imaging. Pettit with assistance from Wilmore reorganized a variety of orbital plumbing tools relocating them from the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/permanent-multipurpose-module/"&gt;Permanent Multipurpose Module&lt;/a&gt; and stowing them in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/zarya-module/"&gt;Zarya module&lt;/a&gt;. Wilmore earlier photographed a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/search/?#q=%22J-SSOD-30%22&amp;amp;i=&amp;amp;p=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;g=&amp;amp;s=&amp;amp;a="&gt;set of CubeSats&lt;/a&gt; deployed into Earth orbit outside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; for education research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; spent his day on space biology research. He first worked out on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=973"&gt;advanced resistive exercise device&lt;/a&gt; then jogged on the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=752"&gt;COLBERT treadmill&lt;/a&gt; before wearing the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7392"&gt;Bio-Monitor headband and vest&lt;/a&gt; for a 48-hour health monitoring session. Afterward, Hague set up a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=894"&gt;research incubators&lt;/a&gt; inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineer Aleksandr Gorbunov checked out gas supply valves for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=1192"&gt;Plasma Kristall-4&lt;/a&gt; space physics experiment that may improve fundamental research methods and spacecraft designs. Gorbunov later explored futuristic spacecraft and robotic piloting techniques future crew members may use on planetary missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e316172.jpg" alt="Week Begins with Spacewalk Preps, Physics, and Biology Research"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/09/week-begins-with-spacewalk-preps-physics-and-biology-research/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spacesuits and Space Biology Fill Day Aboard Space Station</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/10/spacesuits-and-space-biology-fill-day-aboard-space-station/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25786" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25786" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/2qyePR6"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25786" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e308289.jpg" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams displays science hardware housing bacteria and yeast samples for a biomanufacturing experiment that may enable the production of food and medicine in space." width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e308289.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e308289.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e308289.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25786" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Astronaut Suni Williams displays science hardware housing bacteria and yeast samples for a biomanufacturing experiment that may enable the production of food and medicine in space.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacesuits and space biology were the main focus on Tuesday as the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; gets ready for a spacewalk and keeps up critical research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner from Roscosmos worked throughout the day inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt; where they are getting ready for the year’s final spacewalk. Vagner first conducted leak checks on Poisk’s airlock hatch where the cosmonauts will exit into the vacuum of space at 10:10 a.m. EST on Thursday, Dec. 19. Next, the duo paired up activating and inspecting their individual Orlan spacesuits, installing batteries, and removing excess gasses and liquids from the suits they will wear during the spacewalk. The cosmonauts are expected to spend about six hours and 40 minutes removing external science experiments and relocating European robotic arm hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; was back inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/quest-airlock/"&gt;Quest airlock&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday checking out and replacing components on a U.S. spacesuit. Afterward, she joined NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; for eye exams with the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=736"&gt;Ultrasound 2&lt;/a&gt; device. The duo took turns scanning each other’s eyes as doctors on the ground monitored in real-time the condition of each astronaut’s cornea, lens, and optic nerve. Wilmore also transferred cargo between the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus&lt;/a&gt; laboratory modules then installed air quality sensors inside Quest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; started his day reconfiguring and cleaning a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7697"&gt;research incubators&lt;/a&gt;, one of which can generate artificial gravity, inside the Kibo lab module. He later joined Wilmore who scanned Pettit’s eyes with the Ultrasound 2 then assisted him with the cargo transfers between Kibo and Columbus. Pettit also reviewed procedures for an upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9126"&gt;cancer and disease detection study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; of NASA explored the potential of &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8907"&gt;micro-algae&lt;/a&gt; as a way to remove carbon dioxide, produce oxygen, and grow food on spacecraft. Hague processed sample containers for installation inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=66"&gt;BioLab&lt;/a&gt; research facility to understand the effects of radiation and microgravity on the micro-algae and learn how to sustain crews on missions to the Moon, Mars, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hague, who is also the commander of the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/nasas-spacex-crew-9/"&gt;SpaceX Crew-9&lt;/a&gt; mission, joined his crewmates Williams, Wilmore, and cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov inside the Dragon crew spacecraft for a departure training session at the end of the day. Hague and Gorbunov launched together on Dragon to the orbital outpost on &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/liftoff-nasas-spacex-crew-9-launches-to-international-space-station/"&gt;Sept. 28&lt;/a&gt;. They will return to Earth in the spring with Williams and Wilmore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about station activities by following the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/"&gt;space station blog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/space_station"&gt;@space_station&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ISS_Research"&gt;@ISS_Research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on X, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ISS"&gt;ISS Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/iss"&gt;ISS Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the latest from NASA delivered every week. Subscribe here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/subscribe"&gt;www.nasa.gov/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/12/blog_iss072e308289.jpg" alt="Spacesuits and Space Biology Fill Day Aboard Space Station"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/10/spacesuits-and-space-biology-fill-day-aboard-space-station/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crew Works Biomedical, Robotics Research and Waits for Dragon Departure</title>
      <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/11/crew-works-biomedical-robotics-research-and-waits-for-dragon-departure/</link>
      <description>
		&lt;figure id="attachment_25605" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25605" style="width: 840px" class="wp-caption alignnone"&gt;&lt;img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25605" src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_dragon_approach_110624.jpg" alt="The SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft is pictured from an external space station camera approaching the orbital outpost above Argentina. Credit: NASA+" width="840" height="472" srcset="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_dragon_approach_110624.jpg 900w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_dragon_approach_110624.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_dragon_approach_110624.jpg?resize=768,432 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px"&gt;&lt;figcaption id="caption-attachment-25605" class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The SpaceX Dragon cargo spacecraft is pictured from an external space station camera approaching the orbital outpost above Argentina. Credit: NASA+&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disease detection, cellular immunity, and free-flying robotics were the top advanced research topics aboard the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/"&gt;International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday. Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/expedition-72/"&gt;Expedition 72&lt;/a&gt; crew members wait to send off a U.S. cargo spacecraft while preparing for the year’s final spacewalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists on the ground are using the orbital outpost’s microgravity environment to learn how to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=9126"&gt;detect genetic mutations and viruses&lt;/a&gt; that can cause illnesses, such as cancer and other diseases, on Earth and in space. NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/donald-r-pettit/"&gt;Don Pettit&lt;/a&gt; processed samples of RNA, a nucleic acid, in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/harmony-module/"&gt;Harmony module&lt;/a&gt;’s maintenance work area for visualization in a handheld fluorescence viewer. Results may enable the quick identification of genetic sequences that can affect human health to better protect astronauts on missions to the Moon, Mars, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/people/nick-hague/"&gt;Nick Hague&lt;/a&gt; began his day collecting his blood and saliva samples. He processed the specimens and stowed some of the samples in a &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=56"&gt;science freezer&lt;/a&gt; and placed others inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=894"&gt;Kubik research incubator&lt;/a&gt; for later analysis. Doctors will study the samples to understand and prevent &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8170"&gt;space-caused cellular stress and tissue damage&lt;/a&gt;. Hague also took off the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=7392"&gt;Bio-Monitor headband and vest&lt;/a&gt; and downloaded the health data collected over two days from the biomedical wearables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/kibo-laboratory-module/"&gt;Kibo laboratory module&lt;/a&gt;, NASA Flight Engineer &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/barry-e-wilmore/"&gt;Butch Wilmore&lt;/a&gt; outfitted the toaster-sized &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1891"&gt;Astrobee robotic free-flyer&lt;/a&gt; with a small docking mechanism for the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/investigation/?#id=8755"&gt;Clingers&lt;/a&gt; technology demonstration. Engineers on the ground monitored the Astrobee as it tested autonomous navigation, docking, and undocking techniques using the Clingers device. Insights may boost space industry standardization of in-space refueling, repair, and manufacturing operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Station Commander &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/astronauts/sunita-williams/"&gt;Suni Williams&lt;/a&gt; from NASA opened up the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/station/research-explorer/facility/?#id=1854"&gt;Materials Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; (MSL) inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/columbus-laboratory-module/"&gt;Columbus laboratory module&lt;/a&gt; troubleshooting its components. The MSL enables safe, high-temperature observations of materials such as metals, polymers, semiconductors, and more in weightlessness to discover new applications and create new materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission managers waved off the planned return of a Dragon resupply spacecraft on Thursday, Dec. 12, due to forecasted unfavorable weather conditions at the splashdown site off the coast of Florida. NASA and SpaceX now are targeting Saturday, Dec. 14, for the next undocking opportunity of NASA’s SpaceX 31&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; commercial resupply services spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA’s live coverage of Dragon’s undocking and departure begins at 10:50 a.m. EST on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/nasas-spacex-31st-commercial-resupply-services-undocking/"&gt;NASA+&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;as the spacecraft autonomously undocks from the Harmony module’s forward port around 11:05 a.m. on Saturday. Learn how to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/general/how-to-stream-nasa-tv/"&gt;watch NASA content&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;through a variety of platforms, including social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscosmos Flight Engineers Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner continued their spacewalk preparations on Wednesday. The duo checked their suits for leaks, tested communications and medical hardware, and installed spacewalking gear inside the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/international-space-station/poisk-mini-research-module-2-yezof/"&gt;Poisk module&lt;/a&gt;. The cosmonauts will exit Poisk into the vacuum of space at 10:10 a.m. EST on Thursday, Dec. 19, and spend about six hours and 40 minutes removing science experiments and relocating robotic hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov began his day working on video and computer hardware throughout the station’s Roscosmos segment. Afterward, he entered the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2021/07/29/new-module-successfully-docks-to-space-station/"&gt;Nauka science module&lt;/a&gt; activating the European robotic arm (ERA) and verifying mission data uploaded to the ERA.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/wp-content/uploads/sites/240/2024/11/blog_dragon_approach_110624.jpg" alt="Crew Works Biomedical, Robotics Research and Waits for Dragon Departure"&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/12/11/crew-works-biomedical-robotics-research-and-waits-for-dragon-departure/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
